<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://junemy.github.io</id>
    <title>June&apos;s blog</title>
    <updated>2019-11-30T01:20:40.441Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://junemy.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://junemy.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>lifelong learner</subtitle>
    <logo>https://junemy.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://junemy.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2019, June&apos;s blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 一个完整的interview]]></title>
        <id>https://junemy.github.io/post/ZEzEtcVZj</id>
        <link href="https://junemy.github.io/post/ZEzEtcVZj">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-29T15:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe height="230" width="260" src="https://www.ximalaya.com/thirdparty/player/sound/player.html?id=232769607&type=red" frameborder=0 allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>对于一个新烤鸭来说，了解考试流程尤为重要，那么上面的音频中的就是一次完整的雅思口语考试。<br>
下面的是问题，大家可以试着自己练习一下，然后跟录音中的进行一些比较额。<br>
P.S. 录音中非9分范文，仅供考参考一下考试形式。</p>
<h1 id="问题">问题：</h1>
<h1 id="part1">Part1</h1>
<p>Can you tell me your full name please?<br>
Can I see your identification please?</p>
<p>Do you live in a house or an apartment?<br>
Is there anything you want to change about your neighborhood?</p>
<p>Clothes<br>
What do you like to wear when you are at home?<br>
What do people in your country like to wear to parties?<br>
Do you like to try different kind of fashion？<br>
Do people in your country usually like to wear formal or casual clothes？<br>
Politeness<br>
Is it important to be polite in your country?<br>
How do children learn good manners？<br>
Who do you think is usually more polite, older or younger people?<br>
Do you think more people are more polite at home with family or with people they don't know?</p>
<h1 id="part-2">Part 2</h1>
<p>Describe a difficult decision that you made.<br>
You should say:<br>
what decision it was<br>
what difficulties you faced<br>
how you made the decision</p>
<p>Have you told anyone else about this?</p>
<h1 id="part-3">Part 3</h1>
<p>What are some decisions that most people need to make these days?<br>
Who do you think usually give the best advice in your culture?<br>
What disadvantages are there when other people give you advice when you have to make a decision?</p>
<p>What are the important things that a teenager has to make decisions about?<br>
How can your age make a difference to the way you approach decision making?</p>
<p>the end~</p>
<p>以上音频内容来自British council<br>
转载本篇文章请联系我，谢谢！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# part 2 段与段之间的连接句]]></title>
        <id>https://junemy.github.io/post/A3XIwfopJ</id>
        <link href="https://junemy.github.io/post/A3XIwfopJ">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-26T06:09:54.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>雅思口语part2通常是由一个话题加四个小问题组成，在考试的时候需要烤鸭们自己讲差不多两分钟，这两分钟的内容输出，说多不多，说少不少，如何让考官可以对我们的内容有一个清晰的了解就需要我们将自己的答案给有组织的呈现出来，那么就会涉及到连接句的使用。</p>
<p>建议烤鸭们不要将心思过度放在这些连接句上，然后背很多非常长，一看就很像是套路句的连接句，比如说：<br>
off the top of my head, the person i ....<br>
when i see this topic, the person....<br>
.....</p>
<p>使用连接句的主要目的是让我们的答案更清晰，方便考官知道我们到底在讲什么，而不是拿那些无比长的套句来冲量，所以我们的主要努力还是要放在内容上，那么在连接句的使用上建议简短，直接即可。</p>
<p>不管我们的答案到底是5段还是4段，都可以借鉴以下的这些句子。</p>
<p>首段</p>
<ol>
<li>well, the person that i'd like to talk about is ....</li>
<li>ok, i'd like to share the story when i ....</li>
<li>well, i'd like to talk about...</li>
</ol>
<p>中间段：</p>
<ol>
<li>as for...</li>
<li>in terms of ...</li>
<li>moving on to...</li>
</ol>
<p>结尾段</p>
<ol>
<li>finally,</li>
<li>in the end</li>
<li>anyway,</li>
</ol>
<p>最后全部讲完以后给考官一个信号词，so, that's it/ that's all my story.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 2019年9-12月雅思口语话题 （二）]]></title>
        <id>https://junemy.github.io/post/1Lxsyq61E</id>
        <link href="https://junemy.github.io/post/1Lxsyq61E">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-21T01:34:05.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1perfume">1.	perfume</h3>
<p>Do you use perfume?<br>
What kind of perfume do you like?<br>
What does perfume mean to you?<br>
Do you give perfume as a gift?</p>
<h3 id="2reading">2.	Reading</h3>
<p>Do you like reading?<br>
What kind of books do you read?<br>
Do you read electronic books?<br>
Do you read books related to your profession?</p>
<h3 id="3smile">3.	Smile</h3>
<p>Do you like to smile?<br>
When do people smile at others?<br>
Do you smile when people take pictures of you?<br>
Can you recognize a fake smile?</p>
<h3 id="4garbage">4.	Garbage</h3>
<p>Why do some people throw garbage on the street?<br>
What do you do with garbage when you are on the street?<br>
How do you feel when you see people throw garbage on the street?<br>
Do you think your city is clean or not?</p>
<h3 id="5visit-relatives">5.	Visit relatives</h3>
<p>Do you often visit your relatives?<br>
What do you do when visiting relatives?<br>
When was the last time you visited a relative?<br>
Why do people visit their relative?</p>
<h3 id="6borrowinglending">6.	Borrowing/lending</h3>
<p>Have you borrowed books from others?<br>
Have you ever borrowed money from others?<br>
Do you like to lend things to others?<br>
How do you feel when people don’t return things they borrowed from you?</p>
<h3 id="7social-networks">7.	Social networks</h3>
<p>Do you like using social networks?<br>
When did you first hear about social networks?<br>
Is social networking popular in your country?<br>
What kind of social networking website do people use in your country?<br>
Are you a social person?<br>
What kind of people do you like to be friends with on those websites?<br>
How often do you use social networking applications?<br>
Why do you use social networking apps?<br>
What are the disadvantages of social networking apps?<br>
Do you think it is good to make friends online?</p>
<h3 id="8math">8.	Math</h3>
<p>When did you start learning math?<br>
Do you like math?<br>
Who taught you math?<br>
Do you often use a calculator?<br>
Do you think it’s difficult to learn mathematics well?<br>
Do you think mathematics is important?<br>
Are girls generally good at mathematic?</p>
<h3 id="9time-management">9.	Time management</h3>
<p>How do you organize your time?<br>
Why do you organize your time?<br>
Would you say you are good at managing your time?<br>
Where did you learn how to organize your time?</p>
<h3 id="10punctuality">10.	Punctuality</h3>
<p>Is punctuality important?<br>
Do you like to wait for others?<br>
What are the advantages of being punctual?<br>
Are you punctual?<br>
Do you like to wear a watch?<br>
How is your time management?<br>
What do you do to improve your time management?</p>
<h3 id="11street-market">11.	Street market</h3>
<p>Are there many street markets in China？<br>
What is the difference between street markets and supermarkets?<br>
Is it a default for the street markets to exist in China？<br>
Do you like street markets? Why?<br>
Why do some people like street markets?<br>
Do you want to go to the street markets in foreign countries?<br>
Have you ever been to street markets in other countries?<br>
Is it different from the street markets in china?<br>
Which one do you prefer, outdoor markets, supermarkets or shopping mall?<br>
Which one do you prefer, street markets or supermarkets, why?<br>
Do you like go to the supermarkets?<br>
Why do people like going to the supermarket?<br>
What do street markets sell?</p>
<h3 id="12outdoor-activities">12.	Outdoor activities</h3>
<p>What do you do in your spare time?<br>
Do you like outdoor activities?<br>
What outdoor activities do you like to do?<br>
How often do you do those activities?<br>
What outdoor sports do you like? why?<br>
How much time do you spend outdoor every week?<br>
How often do you do outdoor activities?<br>
What types of outdoor activities are popular in your country?<br>
Do you prefer to be indoors or outdoors?<br>
Did you like to go outside when you were young?<br>
Did you often go over to your friends’ house when you were young?<br>
Is it important for children to play outdoors?</p>
<h3 id="13spare-time-with-family">13.	Spare time with family</h3>
<p>Do you like to spend time with your family?<br>
What do you usually do when you are free?<br>
What do you and your family like to do in the spare time?<br>
Do you think you will spend more time with your family?</p>
<h3 id="14traveltrip">14.	Travel/trip</h3>
<p>Do you like travelling?<br>
What form of transport do you prepare your travel?<br>
Have you ever travelled alone?<br>
What places in china (or would be) attractive for foreigners to travel to?<br>
Which cities have you travelled to?<br>
What kind of cities do you like to travel to?<br>
What is the place that left you the deepest impression when traveling?</p>
<h3 id="15rainy-days">15.	Rainy days</h3>
<p>Do people like rainy days?<br>
Do you often take raincoats or umbrellas with you?<br>
Does it rain much in china? (where? When?<br>
Is there any part of china where it doesn’t rain much?<br>
When (in what month/season) does it rain most in your hometown?<br>
In which season does it rain most in other parts of china?<br>
Can you remember any time when it rained particularly heavily in your hometown?<br>
Will the rain change your mood?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 2019年9-12月雅思口语话题 （一）]]></title>
        <id>https://junemy.github.io/post/part1</id>
        <link href="https://junemy.github.io/post/part1">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-20T14:27:46.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1-amusement-park">1. Amusement park</h3>
<p>Do you like going to amusement parks?<br>
How often do you go to amusement parks?<br>
What do you usually do at amusement parks?<br>
Do you think facilities in amusement parks are safe to get on?</p>
<h3 id="2makeup">2.	Makeup</h3>
<p>Do you often wear makeup?<br>
What does wear makeup mean to you?<br>
Would you give makeup as gifts?<br>
How do you feel about man wearing makeup?</p>
<h3 id="3fatiguetiredness">3.	Fatigue/tiredness</h3>
<p>What makes you feel tired?<br>
What do you do when you are tired?<br>
Who do you prefer to talk to about your worries, friends or families?<br>
Do you want to talk to others when you are tired?</p>
<h3 id="4eating">4.	Eating</h3>
<p>How often do you eat with your family members?<br>
Do you enjoy having healthy foods?<br>
Do you and your family eat out often?<br>
Do you prefer eating out or cook at home?</p>
<h3 id="5weather-sunshine">5.	Weather (sunshine)</h3>
<p>Do you enjoy sunshine?<br>
What do you usually do on sunny days?<br>
Have you ever used sunscreen?<br>
Will you enjoy living in a place where the weather is different?</p>
<h3 id="6outdoor-activity-forest">6.	Outdoor activity (forest)</h3>
<p>Do you prefer indoor or outdoor activities?<br>
What do people like to do outdoors?<br>
Do you like walking in a forest when you are free?<br>
When was the last time you went to a forest?</p>
<h3 id="7hair-cut">7.	Hair cut</h3>
<p>When was the last time you got a haircut?<br>
What hairstyle did you go for?<br>
How often do you change your hairstyle?<br>
Were you happy about the last haircut you got?</p>
<h3 id="8jeans">8.	Jeans</h3>
<p>How often do you wear jeans?<br>
Do you like wearing jeans?<br>
Why do you think jeans are popular?<br>
Do you think jeans will be more popular in the future?</p>
<h3 id="9visiting-hometown">9.	Visiting hometown</h3>
<p>How often do you go back to your hometown?<br>
How often do you visit your grandparents?<br>
What do you bring as gifts when you go back for visits?<br>
Do you enjoy visiting friends more or families more?</p>
<h3 id="10vacation">10．Vacation</h3>
<p>How often do you go on vacation?<br>
Do you want a long or short vacation?<br>
What was the most exciting thing you experienced in a trip?<br>
What is your dream vacation like?</p>
<h3 id="11languages">11.	Languages</h3>
<p>How many languages do you speak?<br>
Do you think it’s difficult to learn a new language?<br>
Why do you learn English?<br>
Are you currently learning other languages?<br>
How did you learn the language you speak?<br>
Do you think English is hard to learn?</p>
<h3 id="12social-media">12.	Social media</h3>
<p>Do you use the social media often?<br>
What do you use the social media for?<br>
Do you think making new friends on social media is a good thing?<br>
Do you think you will use social media more or less frequently?</p>
<h3 id="13island">13.	Island</h3>
<p>Have you ever been on an island?<br>
Are there islands in your country?<br>
Do you want to live on an island?<br>
What would you like to do while you are on an island?</p>
<h3 id="14voice">14.	Voice</h3>
<p>Has your voice ever changed?<br>
Do you like your own voice?<br>
Do you enjoy recording your voice and listening to it?<br>
Does your voice sound similar to your parents’?</p>
<h3 id="15walk">15.	Walk</h3>
<p>Do you walk a lot?<br>
Do you walk more often than in the past?<br>
Do you think people will walk more or not in the future?<br>
Where do you usually take a walk?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>