<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog</id>
    <title>June&apos;s blog</title>
    <updated>2019-12-26T15:03:09.615Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog"/>
    <link rel="self" href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>lifelong learner</subtitle>
    <logo>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2019, June&apos;s blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[# #雅思# #词汇#  2019年9月-12月]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/AEA4vKq30</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/AEA4vKq30">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-20T09:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="amusement-park">Amusement park</h1>
<p>在游乐园里玩不要用play<br>
a ride/rides; to ride</p>
<p><strong>可以玩的项目</strong><br>
a Ferris wheel<br>
a roller coaster<br>
bumper cars<br>
a drop tower<br>
a ‘haunted house’<br>
a merry-go-round<br>
a shooting gallery</p>
<p><strong>玩的动作</strong><br>
have all sorts of adventures<br>
go for a spin in some bumper cars<br>
go for a ride in the xxx<br>
enjoy firework display in the evening<br>
throw myself into various entertainment facilities<br>
watch singing and dancing performance<br>
take pictures with my favorite cartoon characters</p>
<p><strong>感受</strong><br>
scary rides<br>
excitement; exciting<br>
they are exhilarating<br>
thrilling<br>
pumped 兴奋<br>
heart-stopping<br>
to scream 尖叫<br>
nausea  n. 恶心，反胃的<br>
nauseous  adj.  恶心的，反胃的<br>
the spinning makes me nauseous. 转来转去的让我想吐。<br>
to vomit<br>
to feel giddy  感到头晕眼花的<br>
fear of heights  恐高<br>
jammed with noisy children<br>
queue up</p>
<p><strong>原因</strong><br>
have a blast for a whole day<br>
it's a getaway from the hectic work/study.<br>
pricy<br>
the best way to escape a monotonous routine and have a stress-free day<br>
foster bonding with friends and family</p>
<p><em><strong>To be continued</strong></em></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#语法# #也#  also, as well, too, either]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/qaOcRWred</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/qaOcRWred">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-14T08:47:34.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在英语中，also, as well, too, either 都有“也”的意思，但是在使用方法上却不尽相同。总的来说，前三个用于表达肯定意思中的“也”，最后一个表达的是否定意思中的“也”。下面，我们就来看看具体的不同之处。</p>
<h1 id="1also">1.	Also</h1>
<p>常用于写作中，少用于口语中<br>
位置：句首，句中&amp;句末</p>
<p>句首：强调后面的句子或是新加入的观点，后面应该加上逗号。</p>
<p><em>It’s very humid. Also, you can easily get sunburnt.<br>
那里（空气）很潮湿，同时，你也很容易晒伤。</em></p>
<p>句中：用作副词，在主语和主动词之间，或者在情态动词&amp;第一个助动词之后。作用是连接之后的从句。</p>
<p><em>She works very hard but she also goes to the gym every week.<br>
她工作很努力，但是她同时也每周都去一次健身房。</em></p>
<p><em>I’ve been working in the garden this week, and I’ve also been reading a lot.<br>
我这周一直在整修花园，我同时也在一直读书。</em></p>
<p>句尾：连接两个短句。在口语中我们常用as well &amp; too替代also。</p>
<p><em>She contacted him in the office but he didn’t answer the phone. His mobile phone was silent also. (or His mobile phone was silent too. or … was silent as well.)<br>
她在办公室里给他打电话，但是他没有接，他的手机是在静音的状态。（用too, as well, 也可以）</em></p>
<h1 id="2as-well">2.	As well</h1>
<p>常用于口语中，少用于写作中<br>
位置：常用于句尾,不要放在句首。</p>
<p><em>I just ignored it. I think everybody else did as well.<br>
<s>Not: As well I think everybody else did.</s></em></p>
<h1 id="3too">3.	Too</h1>
<p>位置：常用于句尾，也可在句中</p>
<p>句尾：<br>
<em>Gill’s having chicken. I’ll probably have chicken too.<br>
Gill 要吃鸡肉，我应该也吃鸡肉。</em></p>
<p><em>She looks really tired and she must be really hungry too.<br>
她看起来很累，她应该也很饿的吧。</em></p>
<p>句中：直接跟在主语之后，如果直接修饰主语的话。不跟在情态动词和助动词之后。</p>
<p><em>I too thought she looked unwell.<br>
我也认为她看起来气色不是很好。</em></p>
<p><em>We, too, have been very pleased to receive the prize on her behalf.<br>
我们也很开心可以代表她领奖。<br>
<s>Not: We have too been very pleased …</s><br>
不是这样的表述方式。</em></p>
<h1 id="4either">4.	Either</h1>
<p>用法一：否定含义的“也”</p>
<p><em>Bill’s not here. I don’t think Dave is either, is he?<br>
bill不在这里，我感觉Dave应该也不在的吧，对不对？<br>
<s>Not: I don’t think Dave is also/as well/too.</s><br>
不是这样的表述方式。</em></p>
<p><em>She doesn’t like eggs and she doesn’t like fish either.<br>
她不喜欢鸡蛋，她也不喜欢鱼。</em></p>
<p><em>It was a really nice hotel, and it wasn’t very expensive either.<br>
这个酒店很好，而且价格也不贵。</em></p>
<p>用法二：either .. or … 提供不同选项或者替代方案</p>
<p><em>We can eat either beef or pork.<br>
我们可以吃牛肉或者猪肉。</em></p>
<p>下面，我们可以看一些小练习额～</p>
<ol>
<li>I must buy a new phone ______.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>Wesley is a strong boy. ______, he is very generous.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>I’m going to Japan next week and my sister’s going _____.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>He can’t surf; he can’t swim ______.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
</ol>
<p>答案是 :</p>
<ol>
<li>B,C</li>
<li>A</li>
<li>B,C</li>
<li>D</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 完美9分答案]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/iy_Ge4zRw</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/iy_Ge4zRw">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-02T11:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>很多小烤鸭们不是很清楚自己的英语会是属于哪个水平的，那么下边的就是一个完美9分答案的展示。建议可以自己先试着回答一下问题，然后拿着自己的跟这个答案对比一下，学习这里面的好词好句，争取转化成是自己的！</p>
<p align="center"><iframe style="float:middle" height="50" width="260"src="https://www.ximalaya.com/thirdparty/player/sound/player.html?id=233698642&type=red" frameborder=0 allowfullscreen></iframe></p >
<h1 id="只有问题">只有问题</h1>
<h2 id="part-1">Part 1</h2>
<p>Can you tell me your full name, please?<br>
can you tell me where you’re from?<br>
Can I see your identification, please?</p>
<p>Can you tell me about the kind of music you like?<br>
Where do you like to listen to music?<br>
Why do you think music is so important in many people’s lives?</p>
<p>What’s the best way to get around your city?<br>
Have you ever learned to drive?<br>
Do you think everybody should learn to drive?</p>
<h2 id="part-2">Part 2</h2>
<p>Describe something difficult you learned to do.<br>
You should say:<br>
– what you learned to do<br>
– how you learned to do it<br>
– why it was difficult<br>
and explain whether you’re glad that you learned to do this or not.</p>
<h2 id="part-3">Part 3</h2>
<p>What motivates people to learn new things?<br>
Do you think the way that people learn new things has changed compared to the past?<br>
How do you think technology will change the way people learn new things in the future?<br>
How can parents or students choose the best school or university?<br>
How do people in your country feel about private education?<br>
Do you think that university education should be free?</p>
<h1 id="问题答案">问题&amp;答案</h1>
<h2 id="part-1-2">Part 1</h2>
<p>Examiner: Hello, my name is ---. This is the IELTS speaking test. Can you tell me your full name, please?<br>
Student: My name’s ---.</p>
<p>Examiner: And can you tell me where you’re from?<br>
Student: I’m from a small town near Northampton, in the UK.</p>
<p>Examiner: Can I see your identification, please?<br>
Student: Yes, of course. Here you are.</p>
<p>Examiner: Okay, thank you very much. Now, in this first part I’d like to know something about you. First of all, can you tell me about the kind of music you like?<br>
Student: Sure, well, I’m a big fan of what you might call alternative electronica. It’s hard to classify, because when you say ‘electronica’, people think of dance music, but I wouldn’t call it that. Basically, I listen to a lot of stuff with hip-hop, funk or disco influences, but most of my friends think my taste in music is a bit weird.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. And, where do you like to listen to music?<br>
Student: I listen to music pretty much any time that I’m at home. So, if I’m doing housework, or cooking, or anything like that, I’ll put some music on. Sometimes I also listen to music on the bus. Especially if I’m going to play sport or to the gym, I’ll listen to some high-energy tunes on the way to get myself pumped up.</p>
<p>Examiner: Yeah, okay. Why do you think music is so important in many people’s lives?<br>
Student: Hmm… That’s a big question… [pause] Well, first of all music has always been part of human culture, so in that sense obviously it’s an important part of our lives. I guess that’s because music can have such a powerful effect on our emotions. Music can lift you up, or inspire you, or make you feel sad. I’d certainly find it hard to live without it!</p>
<p>Examiner: Uh-huh. I’d like to move on and talk about transport. What’s the best way to get around your city?<br>
Student: I live in quite a small town, so it’s very easy to get around. You can walk or cycle to a lot of places, although some roads are a bit dangerous for bikes. There are buses which are fairly reliable, but they’re not the fastest way to get around. Finally, you can take a taxi or an Uber if you want to get somewhere fast and you don’t mind paying a bit extra.</p>
<p>Examiner: Alright. And, have you ever learned to drive?<br>
Student: Yes, I learned in the UK as soon as I was old enough, although I have to say I haven’t driven for several years! I’m not sure if you’d want to get in a car with me, but I guess I’d pick it up again quite quickly. There’s just not much point in having a car where I am now, because I can walk or ride my bike around town, and take public transport if I want to go somewhere else, for the weekend or whatever.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. Do you think everybody should learn to drive?<br>
Student: Er… That’s a strange idea. I think it’s up to each person to decide. It can be very useful in some places. For example, where I grew up in the UK… It’s a rural area, and if you don’t have a car you’re pretty isolated. If you live somewhere like that, you should probably learn to drive. But, it’s still a choice, right?</p>
<h2 id="part-2-2">Part 2</h2>
<p>Examiner: Now, I’m going to give you a topic and I’d like you to talk about it for one to two minutes. You have one minute to think about what you are going to say. You can make some notes to help you if you wish.</p>
<p>Describe something difficult you learned to do.<br>
You should say:<br>
– what you learned to do<br>
– how you learned to do it<br>
– why it was difficult<br>
and explain whether you’re glad that you learned to do this or not.</p>
<p>Examiner: Are you ready?<br>
Student: Yes.<br>
Examiner: Okay, please tell me about something difficult you learned to do.</p>
<p>Student: So, I’m going to tell you about learning to drive a car with manual transmission. I’m from the States, and almost no one drives a manual there; most cars are automatic. When I came to Europe, I found it was totally the opposite here; driving a manual is the norm, and automatics are rare. I guess here they’re associated with very expensive, luxury cars. Anyway, I had to learn to drive stick, and it was so difficult! It was doubly hard because I already knew how to drive, so it felt extra frustrating to be behind the wheel but unable to do the things I would normally do. Maybe it wasn’t a good idea but I didn’t get any help; I could have gone to a driving school but I didn’t. I just practiced and tried to learn by myself, by driving around car parks and open spaces and things like that. That was okay, but when I went out and drove properly, on the streets with traffic, it was super stressful. I just couldn’t get the clutch right, and then I’d stall and I’d be stressing out while everyone was honking at me. I can’t say that I’m glad that I learned it. I mean, I just learned to do it because I had to, and I didn’t enjoy the experience! If it were up to me, I’d rather just have an automatic car.</p>
<p>Examiner: Thank you. So, what do you use your car for?<br>
Student: Mostly for getting to work. I live quite far from the nearest metro station and the bus lines aren’t good, so it’s much easier to drive. Sometimes we go out of town for the weekends, too.</p>
<h2 id="part-3-2">Part 3</h2>
<p>Examiner: Right, I’d like to ask some questions related to this topic. First, let’s talk about learning new things. What motivates people to learn new things?<br>
Student: Wow… that’s a big question! Well, there are lots of reasons. The main one I guess is just necessity. For example, if you want to work in a particular field, you’ll need some specific training, skills, qualifications… Then, when you start a new job, you generally have to adapt and learn a lot of new things, even if you came in with a lot of theoretical knowledge. What else? I think also interest is important… I mean, people learn to do new things because they’re interested in them or they find something enjoyable. For example, no one needs to learn to play a musical instrument, but a lot of people do so because it brings them pleasure.</p>
<p>Examiner: Do you think the way that people learn new things has changed compared to the past?<br>
Student: Absolutely. Of course, the Internet and the development of smartphones and other new technologies have had a huge influence. We all have easy access to so much information now, which wasn’t the case in the past at all. Before, people would need to dedicate a lot of time and effort to finding an expert, or doing research in order to learn about something new. Now, you can find tutorials online, ask people for help in discussion forums, and things like that. So, it’s a big difference, but I think it’s mostly for the better.</p>
<p>Examiner: How do you think technology will change the way people learn new things in the future?<br>
Student: Hmm… I’m not sure. I think we’ll see the same trends developing… What I mean is: the big changes have already happened, but I don’t think they’ve run their course yet. So, a lot of people still have the idea that you learn something by going to a class, reading books, etc., and they haven’t realised that you just have more options nowadays. To tie all this together, I think that in the future, education and learning will be more globalised and democratic, in that everybody will have similar opportunities to learn. I suppose that might mean that formal education diminishes in significance, but I’m not sure that will actually happen.</p>
<p>Examiner: Okay, let’s move on to talk about school and education. How can parents or students choose the best school or university?<br>
Student: In my experience, the only way to know what a school or university is really like is to talk to people who already study there and see what they say. Of course, you can go and look around, but I don’t think you can learn very much just by walking around a school. If you talk to some of the staff and students, you can get a feel of what kind of establishment it is, and whether it’s a good fit for you, or your child, whoever you’re talking about.</p>
<p>Examiner: Mm-hmm. How do people in your country feel about private education?<br>
Student: Huh… I really don’t know. I went to a public school, and so did everyone I know. It’s not really a topic which comes up that much, you know? Personally, I don’t have strong opinions; if someone wants to pay to send their child to a private school, then why not? Given that there aren’t that many private schools, it’s just not something that people are so aware of.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. Do you think that university education should be free?<br>
Student: Definitely, yes. In the USA, university is insanely expensive; parents have to start saving up from the moment their child is born. I think this leads to elitist outcomes… I mean that the richest kids go to the best universities, and if you don’t have a lot of money behind you, your options are more limited. That said, I realize that graduates tend to earn more, so it might be fairer to have some kind of graduate tax, so that the people who erm… benefit from higher education also help to fund it. That seems to me to be the fairest solution.<br>
Examiner: Thank you. That’s the end of the speaking test.</p>
<p>好的，看完了吗？自己感觉怎么样呢？要注意积累好的用法额！～<br>
学习之路漫漫，加油！～</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 一个完整的interview]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/ZEzEtcVZj</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/ZEzEtcVZj">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-29T15:33:24.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p align="center"><iframe style="float:middle" height="50" width="260"src="https://www.ximalaya.com/thirdparty/player/sound/player.html?id=232769607&type=red" frameborder=0 allowfullscreen></iframe></p >
<p>对于一个新烤鸭来说，了解考试流程尤为重要，那么上面的音频中的就是一次完整的雅思口语考试。<br>
下面的是问题，大家可以试着自己练习一下，然后跟录音中的进行一些比较额。<br>
PS 录音中非9分范文，仅供考参考一下考试形式。</p>
<h1 id="问题">问题：</h1>
<h1 id="part1">Part1</h1>
<p>Can you tell me your full name please?<br>
Can I see your identification please?</p>
<p>Do you live in a house or an apartment?<br>
Is there anything you want to change about your neighborhood?</p>
<p>Clothes</p>
<p>What do you like to wear when you are at home?<br>
What do people in your country like to wear to parties?<br>
Do you like to try different kind of fashion？<br>
Do people in your country usually like to wear formal or casual clothes？</p>
<p>Politeness</p>
<p>Is it important to be polite in your country?<br>
How do children learn good manners？<br>
Who do you think is usually more polite, older or younger people?<br>
Do you think more people are more polite at home with family or with people they don't know?</p>
<h1 id="part-2">Part 2</h1>
<p>Describe a difficult decision that you made.<br>
You should say:<br>
what decision it was<br>
what difficulties you faced<br>
how you made the decision</p>
<p>Have you told anyone else about this?</p>
<h1 id="part-3">Part 3</h1>
<p>What are some decisions that most people need to make these days?<br>
Who do you think usually give the best advice in your culture?<br>
What disadvantages are there when other people give you advice when you have to make a decision?</p>
<p>What are the important things that a teenager has to make decisions about?<br>
How can your age make a difference to the way you approach decision making?</p>
<p>the end~</p>
<p>以上音频内容来自British council<br>
转载本篇文章请联系我，谢谢！</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# part 2 段与段之间的连接句]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/A3XIwfopJ</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/A3XIwfopJ">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-26T06:09:54.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>雅思口语part2通常是由一个话题加四个小问题组成，在考试的时候需要烤鸭们自己讲差不多两分钟，这两分钟的内容输出，说多不多，说少不少，如何让考官可以对我们的内容有一个清晰的了解就需要我们将自己的答案给有组织的呈现出来，那么就会涉及到连接句的使用。</p>
<p>建议烤鸭们不要将心思过度放在这些连接句上，然后背很多非常长，一看就很像是套路句的连接句，比如说：<br>
off the top of my head, the person i ....<br>
when i see this topic, the person....<br>
.....</p>
<p>使用连接句的主要目的是让我们的答案更清晰，方便考官知道我们到底在讲什么，而不是拿那些无比长的套句来冲量，所以我们的主要努力还是要放在内容上，那么在连接句的使用上建议简短，直接即可。</p>
<p>不管我们的答案到底是5段还是4段，都可以借鉴以下的这些句子。</p>
<p>首段</p>
<ol>
<li>well, the person that i'd like to talk about is ....</li>
<li>ok, i'd like to share the story when i ....</li>
<li>well, i'd like to talk about...</li>
</ol>
<p>中间段：</p>
<ol>
<li>as for...</li>
<li>in terms of ...</li>
<li>moving on to...</li>
</ol>
<p>结尾段</p>
<ol>
<li>finally,</li>
<li>in the end</li>
<li>anyway,</li>
</ol>
<p>最后全部讲完以后给考官一个信号词，so, that's it/ that's all my story.</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 2019年9-12月雅思口语话题 （二）]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/1Lxsyq61E</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/1Lxsyq61E">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-21T01:34:05.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1perfume">1.	perfume</h3>
<p>Do you use perfume?<br>
What kind of perfume do you like?<br>
What does perfume mean to you?<br>
Do you give perfume as a gift?</p>
<h3 id="2reading">2.	Reading</h3>
<p>Do you like reading?<br>
What kind of books do you read?<br>
Do you read electronic books?<br>
Do you read books related to your profession?</p>
<h3 id="3smile">3.	Smile</h3>
<p>Do you like to smile?<br>
When do people smile at others?<br>
Do you smile when people take pictures of you?<br>
Can you recognize a fake smile?</p>
<h3 id="4garbage">4.	Garbage</h3>
<p>Why do some people throw garbage on the street?<br>
What do you do with garbage when you are on the street?<br>
How do you feel when you see people throw garbage on the street?<br>
Do you think your city is clean or not?</p>
<h3 id="5visit-relatives">5.	Visit relatives</h3>
<p>Do you often visit your relatives?<br>
What do you do when visiting relatives?<br>
When was the last time you visited a relative?<br>
Why do people visit their relative?</p>
<h3 id="6borrowinglending">6.	Borrowing/lending</h3>
<p>Have you borrowed books from others?<br>
Have you ever borrowed money from others?<br>
Do you like to lend things to others?<br>
How do you feel when people don’t return things they borrowed from you?</p>
<h3 id="7social-networks">7.	Social networks</h3>
<p>Do you like using social networks?<br>
When did you first hear about social networks?<br>
Is social networking popular in your country?<br>
What kind of social networking website do people use in your country?<br>
Are you a social person?<br>
What kind of people do you like to be friends with on those websites?<br>
How often do you use social networking applications?<br>
Why do you use social networking apps?<br>
What are the disadvantages of social networking apps?<br>
Do you think it is good to make friends online?</p>
<h3 id="8math">8.	Math</h3>
<p>When did you start learning math?<br>
Do you like math?<br>
Who taught you math?<br>
Do you often use a calculator?<br>
Do you think it’s difficult to learn mathematics well?<br>
Do you think mathematics is important?<br>
Are girls generally good at mathematic?</p>
<h3 id="9time-management">9.	Time management</h3>
<p>How do you organize your time?<br>
Why do you organize your time?<br>
Would you say you are good at managing your time?<br>
Where did you learn how to organize your time?</p>
<h3 id="10punctuality">10.	Punctuality</h3>
<p>Is punctuality important?<br>
Do you like to wait for others?<br>
What are the advantages of being punctual?<br>
Are you punctual?<br>
Do you like to wear a watch?<br>
How is your time management?<br>
What do you do to improve your time management?</p>
<h3 id="11street-market">11.	Street market</h3>
<p>Are there many street markets in China？<br>
What is the difference between street markets and supermarkets?<br>
Is it a default for the street markets to exist in China？<br>
Do you like street markets? Why?<br>
Why do some people like street markets?<br>
Do you want to go to the street markets in foreign countries?<br>
Have you ever been to street markets in other countries?<br>
Is it different from the street markets in china?<br>
Which one do you prefer, outdoor markets, supermarkets or shopping mall?<br>
Which one do you prefer, street markets or supermarkets, why?<br>
Do you like go to the supermarkets?<br>
Why do people like going to the supermarket?<br>
What do street markets sell?</p>
<h3 id="12outdoor-activities">12.	Outdoor activities</h3>
<p>What do you do in your spare time?<br>
Do you like outdoor activities?<br>
What outdoor activities do you like to do?<br>
How often do you do those activities?<br>
What outdoor sports do you like? why?<br>
How much time do you spend outdoor every week?<br>
How often do you do outdoor activities?<br>
What types of outdoor activities are popular in your country?<br>
Do you prefer to be indoors or outdoors?<br>
Did you like to go outside when you were young?<br>
Did you often go over to your friends’ house when you were young?<br>
Is it important for children to play outdoors?</p>
<h3 id="13spare-time-with-family">13.	Spare time with family</h3>
<p>Do you like to spend time with your family?<br>
What do you usually do when you are free?<br>
What do you and your family like to do in the spare time?<br>
Do you think you will spend more time with your family?</p>
<h3 id="14traveltrip">14.	Travel/trip</h3>
<p>Do you like travelling?<br>
What form of transport do you prepare your travel?<br>
Have you ever travelled alone?<br>
What places in china (or would be) attractive for foreigners to travel to?<br>
Which cities have you travelled to?<br>
What kind of cities do you like to travel to?<br>
What is the place that left you the deepest impression when traveling?</p>
<h3 id="15rainy-days">15.	Rainy days</h3>
<p>Do people like rainy days?<br>
Do you often take raincoats or umbrellas with you?<br>
Does it rain much in china? (where? When?<br>
Is there any part of china where it doesn’t rain much?<br>
When (in what month/season) does it rain most in your hometown?<br>
In which season does it rain most in other parts of china?<br>
Can you remember any time when it rained particularly heavily in your hometown?<br>
Will the rain change your mood?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 2019年9-12月雅思口语话题 （一）]]></title>
        <id>http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/part1</id>
        <link href="http://calvincheung.coding.me/juneBlog/post/part1">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-11-20T14:27:46.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1-amusement-park">1. Amusement park</h3>
<p>Do you like going to amusement parks?<br>
How often do you go to amusement parks?<br>
What do you usually do at amusement parks?<br>
Do you think facilities in amusement parks are safe to get on?</p>
<h3 id="2makeup">2.	Makeup</h3>
<p>Do you often wear makeup?<br>
What does wear makeup mean to you?<br>
Would you give makeup as gifts?<br>
How do you feel about man wearing makeup?</p>
<h3 id="3fatiguetiredness">3.	Fatigue/tiredness</h3>
<p>What makes you feel tired?<br>
What do you do when you are tired?<br>
Who do you prefer to talk to about your worries, friends or families?<br>
Do you want to talk to others when you are tired?</p>
<h3 id="4eating">4.	Eating</h3>
<p>How often do you eat with your family members?<br>
Do you enjoy having healthy foods?<br>
Do you and your family eat out often?<br>
Do you prefer eating out or cook at home?</p>
<h3 id="5weather-sunshine">5.	Weather (sunshine)</h3>
<p>Do you enjoy sunshine?<br>
What do you usually do on sunny days?<br>
Have you ever used sunscreen?<br>
Will you enjoy living in a place where the weather is different?</p>
<h3 id="6outdoor-activity-forest">6.	Outdoor activity (forest)</h3>
<p>Do you prefer indoor or outdoor activities?<br>
What do people like to do outdoors?<br>
Do you like walking in a forest when you are free?<br>
When was the last time you went to a forest?</p>
<h3 id="7hair-cut">7.	Hair cut</h3>
<p>When was the last time you got a haircut?<br>
What hairstyle did you go for?<br>
How often do you change your hairstyle?<br>
Were you happy about the last haircut you got?</p>
<h3 id="8jeans">8.	Jeans</h3>
<p>How often do you wear jeans?<br>
Do you like wearing jeans?<br>
Why do you think jeans are popular?<br>
Do you think jeans will be more popular in the future?</p>
<h3 id="9visiting-hometown">9.	Visiting hometown</h3>
<p>How often do you go back to your hometown?<br>
How often do you visit your grandparents?<br>
What do you bring as gifts when you go back for visits?<br>
Do you enjoy visiting friends more or families more?</p>
<h3 id="10vacation">10．Vacation</h3>
<p>How often do you go on vacation?<br>
Do you want a long or short vacation?<br>
What was the most exciting thing you experienced in a trip?<br>
What is your dream vacation like?</p>
<h3 id="11languages">11.	Languages</h3>
<p>How many languages do you speak?<br>
Do you think it’s difficult to learn a new language?<br>
Why do you learn English?<br>
Are you currently learning other languages?<br>
How did you learn the language you speak?<br>
Do you think English is hard to learn?</p>
<h3 id="12social-media">12.	Social media</h3>
<p>Do you use the social media often?<br>
What do you use the social media for?<br>
Do you think making new friends on social media is a good thing?<br>
Do you think you will use social media more or less frequently?</p>
<h3 id="13island">13.	Island</h3>
<p>Have you ever been on an island?<br>
Are there islands in your country?<br>
Do you want to live on an island?<br>
What would you like to do while you are on an island?</p>
<h3 id="14voice">14.	Voice</h3>
<p>Has your voice ever changed?<br>
Do you like your own voice?<br>
Do you enjoy recording your voice and listening to it?<br>
Does your voice sound similar to your parents’?</p>
<h3 id="15walk">15.	Walk</h3>
<p>Do you walk a lot?<br>
Do you walk more often than in the past?<br>
Do you think people will walk more or not in the future?<br>
Where do you usually take a walk?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>