<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://JuneMY.github.io</id>
    <title>June&apos;s blog</title>
    <updated>2020-01-30T08:00:12.886Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://JuneMY.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://JuneMY.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>lifelong learner</subtitle>
    <logo>https://JuneMY.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://JuneMY.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, June&apos;s blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[# 雅思# 2020年1-4月口语答案sample answers--part1]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/XU3Zjny</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/XU3Zjny">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-01-30T06:24:36.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>哈喽，2020年1月的结尾，但是我真的希望可以重启一下，这个年的开始，不是很尽人意。最近我的心情有些低落，但是想造福一下或许同在焦虑心情下的小烤鸭们，所以免费发放一些这个季度的雅思口语答案。需要告诉大家的是，一. 这个答案不是我--这个单打独斗的普通英语学习者写的（非原创）；二. 既然这个答案在市面上流通的这么广，那么肯定还有很多人会有，为了避免重复的风险，建议参考这个答案小伙伴们一定要适当调整一下说法，不要无脑地死背。同时附上音频，希望可以帮助到大家的语音练习。</p>
<iframe height="40" width="260" src="https://www.ximalaya.com/thirdparty/player/sound/player.html?id=247821352&type=red" frameborder=0 allowfullscreen></iframe>
<h1 id="work-or-study常考题">Work or Study(常考题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Why did you choose that subject?<br>
I am majoring in International Business. I chose my major subject of study based on my aptitude in studying economics, accounting, and languages, my interest in travel, and advice from my parents and teachers. I felt this major area of study would prepare me for a career that I would find interesting and that I could be successful in.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is it interesting?<br>
I truly enjoy my courses because they are so interesting. There are a few courses that are more difficult for me than others, but I find if I put more time and effort into studying, I am able do well in them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What subjects are you studying?<br>
This year, I’m taking advanced classes in Finance, Macroeconomics, English, and Information Technology. I am also taking a class in Modern European History because I thought this would be interesting.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you prefer to study in the mornings or in the afternoon?<br>
I prefer to study in the afternoon. I feel more alert in the afternoon than I do in the morning or the evening. I seem to be able to read, and comprehend more, in less time.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are you looking forward to working?<br>
I am definitely looking forward to using the things I have learned in school in my career. I’m also looking forward to making money to support myself.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like your subject?<br>
I love my subject because it is so interesting. I find the more I learn, the more I find interesting about it! I think everything I am learning will be useful in my career.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What work do you do?<br>
I recently started as a research assistant at a large international advertising firm. It’s an entry level position where I find statistics about the likes and dislikes of different age groups in a specific country that our client is looking to do business in.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Why did you choose to do that type of work?<br>
While this is not the final job that I was hoping for, it is a solid entry-level position in a firm that does the kind of work I am interested in. I enjoy gathering the statistics knowing that they will be used to make important decisions in marketing our client’s product. I feel there is a lot of room for promotion here in this company as well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you miss being a student?<br>
I didn’t think that I would, but I do.As much as I like my job and I am grateful to have it, it is a big change. I am meeting new people and learning new responsibilities; my daily schedule is very different, but I need to expect a period of adjustment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like your job?<br>
I really enjoy my job. I think the work is interesting and look forward to learning more. I like all of the people I work with. There are two other research assistants who were hired the same time I was and I enjoy working with them.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="home-常考题">Home (常考题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Can you describe the place where you live?<br>
I live in a high rise apartment building on the 5th floor overlooking the street with apartment buildings on either side. We have a balcony where we keep many of our plants and sometimes we’ll sit there in the evening.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How long have you live there?<br>
I have lived there for 18 years. I was born there.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Who do you live with?<br>
I live with my parents, my sister, and my dog. Sometimes my grandparents or aunt will visit us and they stay with us in our home.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you plan to live there for a long time?<br>
I’m hoping after I finish my education, I find a job and I can find my own home. Housing is expensive, so I may be home with my parents longer than I plan to be.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the difference between where you are living now and where you have lived in the past?<br>
I haven’t lived anywhere else. I have always lived here. My parents lived in a smaller apartment in a building nearby before I was born, but they moved here because they needed more room.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you prefer living in a house or a flat?<br>
I prefer living in a flat because it is so much more convenient, and neighbours seem much more friendly. Perhaps I like it because this is what I am accustomed to.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In the future, what type of place would you like to live in?<br>
I would like to live in a flat on the very top floor of a building. I think it would be quieter and we wouldn’t be able hear as much street noise and the view, especially at night, would be spectacular.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kind of neighbourhood /environment/surroundings/home would you like to live in?<br>
I like living in the city where I am. I like the convenience of being very close to public transportation so I can go where ever I need to go. I like my neighbourhood because we have a variety of young people and old people. It’s our own community.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you usually do in your house/flat/room?<br>
We eat, sleep, and basically live together there. When we are all at home, we sometimes do things together, like watching sports on TV, other times we will go to our room to study or listen to music.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Which room does your family spend most of the time in?<br>
We spend most of our time in the living room. We will watch TV there or play games while lying on the floor. It’s the sunniest room in the house, so it is very pleasant to be in.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What part of your home do you like the most?<br>
I like my bedroom the most in my home. I have it decorated to my taste and feel safe and calm whenever I go into it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are the transport facilities to your home very good?<br>
Absolutely, that’s one of the reasons I like our neighbourhood. It only takes a few minutes to walk to the bus stop and from there, I can get anywhere in the city.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="hometown常考题">Hometown(常考题)</h1>
<p>1.What’s (the name of) your hometown?<br>
I live in Guangzhou. It is located in the Guangdong Province. and is known as the City of Flowers.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>
<p>Is that a big city or a small place?<br>
It is the third largest city in China. It has a population of over 13 million people. It’s a big place.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Please describe your hometown a little.<br>
It is the educational and cultural centre of Southern China. It’s also known as the City of Flowers because there are evergreens and flowers in bloom year round because of its climate. It’s a pretty city.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How long have you lived there?<br>
I have lived here all of my life, for eighteen years. My parents have lived here all of their lives too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like it?<br>
I like it very much. Of course, this is all I have ever known, but whenever my family travels anywhere, I am always happiest when I return home.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like living there?<br>
I like living here because my family is here, my grandparents and aunt live here too. I like the climate because it never gets really cold. I don’t really like all of the rain we get in the summer, but even then, the rain keeps the air cleaner.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you like (the most) about your hometown?<br>
I really like the food. The Cantonese food is excellent and there are so many other kinds of international restaurants to try. I also really enjoy Thai food.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there anything you dislike about it?<br>
The humidity gets things damp in the house, so we have to use air conditioning a lot of the time. I don’t really like air conditioning, but we don’t have a choice but to use it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think you will continue living there for a long time? / 10. Do you plan to continue living there? ( Combined two similar questions as one)<br>
I want to go abroad to study after I graduate from high school. I want to see what other cities and countries have to offer and then I’ll decide.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="the-area-you-live-in常考题">The area you live in(常考题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like the area that you live in?<br>
I love the area that I live in. I am so lucky that we have so much to do which are very close to us! Also, there is public transportation just one block from my building. Everything is so convenient!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are some changes in the area recently?<br>
Over the past few years, some new restaurants have opened nearby which make eating out more convenient for everyone in the area. Also, last year, improvements were made to the park near my house. Some older trees were trimmed and some new varieties of trees were planted.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you know any famous people in your area?<br>
Well, I really don’t think any famous people live near me. I have never heard of or met any famous person in my neighbourhood. I guess it’s because the area I am living in is an area for middle income families, not for famous people who have much higher salaries.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where do you like to go in that area?<br>
Like I said earlier, there are some new restaurants in the area. They are family-style restaurants, so they are the great places to go with my family for relaxed meals. Also, the park has always been a pleasant place to go. Everything I need or want is within walking distance to my home.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="music">Music</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>When do you listen to music?<br>
I listen to music whenever I can. I enjoy listening to music when I'm on public transportation, going to and from school. I also like to listen to music sometimes when I'm studying. It helps to block out things in the background so I'm able to focus better.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How much time do you spend listening to music every day?<br>
I hadn't really thought about this until this question. I think I spend about 2 to 3 hours a day. I listen to it on public transportation and then when I study, but not all the time when I study. Sometimes it's distracting when I'm studying, but I would say 2 to 3 hours a day is a fair estimate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kinds of music do you like to listen to?<br>
I really enjoy K-pop, the energy and the lyrics, it’s just so lively and makes me feel good. I also like to listen to slower songs that have a deeper story like a ballad or something- a lot of fun to listen to a ballad. I also like to listen to instrumental music where there are no words, I sometimes find that to be very soothing when I'm trying to study</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What’s your favourite kind of music?<br>
Without question my favourite music is K-pop. You can't listen to it without enjoying it. It's lively and it makes you feel good and when you're listening to it you're tapping your foot and just getting ready to be excited for the rest of your day. It just always puts me in a good mood.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever been to a concert before?<br>
Sadly, I have not been to a concert, but I'd like to go to one soon. Concerts are expensive but I'm saving up money and I have a few concerts that I have that in mind that I'd like to go to.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="tea-and-coffee">Tea and coffee</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do Chinese people like to drink tea or coffee?<br>
I think more Chinese people prefer to drink tea than coffee. I know my family does. There are so many more flavours of tea that people can enjoy, and that’s why it is more popular.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you prepare tea or coffee for the guests at home?<br>
I prepare and serve tea for guests at home. My mother will make coffee for the few guests who prefer coffee, because I don’t know how to make it properly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When was the last time you drank tea or coffee?<br>
I drank some green tea this morning. I have tea every morning. When I get home from school, I will often have an herbal tea. I have only tried coffee once, and frankly, I just don’t like it. It tastes very bitter to me.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="patience">Patience</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Were you patient when you were young?<br>
No, I was not patient at all when I was young. I remember having trouble waiting for meals and interrupting my parents for attention when they were busy. I cried and shouted when I was impatient and could not be quiet at all.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you feel when other people are not patient?<br>
When younger children are impatient, it doesn’t bother me because I understand they are still learning. However, I get upset when older children and adults aren’t patient. It’s important to be respectful of other people.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Were you less or more patience when you are angry?<br>
I am more patient when I am angry. This is because I always walk away until I am calmer. Then, I won’t do or say things that I may regret later. Walking away forces me to be calmer, so then I will be more patient.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="public-holiday">Public holiday</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>How many public holidays do you have in China?<br>
There are seven public holidays we can enjoy in China. If it’s counted by days, there are 11 public holidays each year. For some of the Chinese, they can enjoy one or half a day for their own holiday. For example, Chinese women enjoy half a day on Women’s Day.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think people need more public holidays?<br>
In my opinion, I think people need more public holidays in China. With more and more work and study burden, Chinese people have less time to enjoy their own hobbies or to attend their family activities nowadays. In addition, more holidays can encourage people to travel more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you usually spend your holidays?<br>
Usually I spend my holidays with my family or my friends. I often gather with family at a restaurant for a morning tea or a meal. Sometimes I will go to the cinema with my good friends for a movie. If I have more holidays, I would rather travel with my family or friends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Which holiday is your favourite?<br>
My favourite holiday, without a doubt, is the Spring Festival which is our Chinese New Year. This is a traditional Chinese festival and it’s the most important holidays for Chinese families. Normally, no matter where we are, we go home to meet our parents and grandparents during these days in a year.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="outdoor">Outdoor</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you prefer to be indoors or outdoors?<br>
Personally, I prefer being outdoors rather than indoors. It feels great to go outside and exercise a bit to maintain a healthy lifestyle. I go to the gym once a week to keep fit and get slimmer. I also do yoga at home for two hours after dinner.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Did you like to go outside when you were young?<br>
I loved to go outside when I was young. There was a park nearby my house when I was in primary school, and my parents would often bring me over there to have fun with my friends. We could spend the whole day in the park without getting bored.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Did you often go over to your friends’ house when you were young?<br>
Yes, I did. My friends invite me to their houses quite a lot and I’ve developed a good relationship with their parents. They often treat me with food and drinks and chat with me about interesting things about their work. The things I learned from them were fascinating.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is it important for children to play outdoors?<br>
I think it’s really important for people to encourage their children to play outdoors. Having some outdoor activities could keep children healthy and strong. Playing outdoors would also help them release some stress that was built during long time studies and school work.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="plan">Plan</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you make plans every day?<br>
Not necessarily. I make plans for myself about things that I must complete each day, and I would mark off any tasks that I’ve completed after doing it. However, I don’t really specify what time I would complete it because it doesn’t really matter to me as long as I complete it in the specified date.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are you good at managing your time?<br>
I’m pretty good at managing my time. I often estimate the amount of time that’s required to finish a certain task, and save some time between each task as little breaks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the latest plan you’ve made?<br>
Just a few days ago, a childhood friend of mine that I haven’t seen for a long time contacted me on social media， asking me to go to a reunion party and see my old primary school friends at a restaurant. It has been quite some time since we parted ways after graduating primary school, so I made plans with them and wrote it in my agenda.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the hardest part about making plans?<br>
The hardest part about making plans for me is when something unexpected occurs and disrupts my original plan. I get stood up by some friends sometimes, because they only tell me an hour before the meetups. It’s really hard to adapt to the sudden change in plan, but I manage to work them out in the end.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="math">Math</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you often use a calculator?<br>
Yes. I do often use a calculator because I feel that it is much faster and convenient when I am doing my Math exercises. Especially when I am solving some complicated algebra questions, a functional calculator can be used as a useful tool for it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are girls generally good at mathematics?<br>
General speaking, girls are not as good as boys at mathematics, especially in the past. But nowadays, there are more and more girls who are interested in the field of Science and Engineering. Some of them are better than boys in the Math study and even at their work.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think it is difficult to learn mathematics well?<br>
Yes. To learn mathematics well requires at least three main factors: interest, diligence, and some degree of abilities in abstract thinking and understanding. This is because compared with other subjects, Math involves more abstract concepts and logical inferences.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think mathematics is important?<br>
Mathematics is an important basic course for students to study because it educates and trains students for their comprehensive ability in abstract thinking, analysis and deduction. It is also the basic tool of the study in all science and engineering. And it plays an important role in the development of human society and propels the society forward.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="travel">Travel</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like travelling?<br>
Yes, I really enjoy travelling, especially by myself. It’s a great way to release all the stress built up at school. I go on some trips to different cities nearby every year during the summer break. I book and order all the tickets and flights by myself, and it’s more affordable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Which cities have you travelled to?<br>
I’ve been to places like Nanjing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Beijing. I enjoyed all the sceneries and food during my trip. I’m still a student, I can’t afford to go to other countries and travel by myself. But I’ve been to Kyoto, Japan with my parents. It was a great family trip and we had a lot of fun there together.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kind of cities do you like to travel to?<br>
I like going to the cities that I could try a lot of delicious food. I really enjoy trying out different food from different cities and experiencing the diffident cultures from places. You could also learn about the histories of places as you have the food. A lot of food such as stinky tofu can date back to Ancient China.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What is the place that left you the deepest impression when travelling?<br>
Japan is probably the most impressive country I’ve ever been to. The clean streets and the politeness of the people have left me the deepest impressions. There was absolutely no garbage that was left on the ground, and all the places I’ve been to were extremely clean and tidy. People were also very polite when they interact with each other.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="market">Market</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What do street markets sell?<br>
Out of all the street markets I’ve been to, almost all of them sell authentic Chinese street food, such as stinky tofu in Hunan, Changfen in Guangdong and other foods that are special in each continent. Street food are usually made to order and offered in smaller sizes for your convenience.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are there many street markets in China?<br>
There are quite a lot of street markets in China. If you go out on the streets in the middle of the night, you could see hundreds of people still sitting on the side of the streets, savouring the snacks they’ve bought from the vendors. It’s an unspoken tradition for people to have midnight snacks in China.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What are the differences between street markets and supermarkets?<br>
Supermarkets tend to sell food that’s made using machines, such as frozen foods and boxed snacks. However, if you go to a local street market in China, you could find tons of homemade and authentic Chinese street food sold in different vendors. They are also cheaper than the frozen food sold in the supermarkets.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you often go to the supermarkets?<br>
I do. Even though supermarkets have a lot of frozen foods in the freezers, they still sell fresh produces. Living alone as a student, I go to the supermarkets once every week to stock up fresh produces in my fridge. I make most of my meals every week, other than the times where I’m incredibly tired after school</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="friends">Friends</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What do you think makes good friends<br>
I think the most important thing about a good friend is the sincerity. If you want to become a good friend, it’s important to actually be sincere in this relationship, and don’t hesitate to show your genuineness to your friends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you keep in contact with friends from your childhood?<br>
I’m actually not in contact with my friends from my childhood anymore. I have their contacts on social media, and I see their posts once in a while, however, we don’t message one another anymore, because it has been so long since the last time I talked to them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kinds of people do you like to make friends with?<br>
I like to make friends with people who are energetic and playful. I enjoy having company so I won’t get too bored during the days. I also like making friends with people who have the same interest as me, because it helps create more topics when having conversations.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think you are a good friend or others?<br>
I think I am a good friend to others, because I am cheerful and I don’t get angry easily. I often joke around with friends, and I’m usually the mood-maker in my group of friends. So I think my friends love to have my company.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="movies">Movies</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What’s your favourite movie?<br>
I have quite a lot of favorite movies, but my most favorite movie would definitely be Spider-man: Into the Spider-verse. It has great graphics and plot, which makes it suitable for all ages to watch. I’ve watched it over five times since it came out.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do your friends like this movie?<br>
Of course, all of my friends who watched it told me they loved it. I went to watch this movie with a friend, and after the movie, we couldn’t stop talking about how great the animation and graphics were, and how beautiful the plot and character settings were.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kinds of movies do you think young people like<br>
I think young people would like movies that have more action and drama. These genres tend to allow young adults to stay focused on the movie, because it’s exciting and attention-grabbing. Movies like a documentary would probably put young people to sleep.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you want to be a movie star?<br>
I used to want to become a movie actor when I was young. I was featured in a school play back when I was in primary school. However, I don’t think I have the ability to become a movie star now that I’ve grown up, and I have no experience in acting ever since elementary.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="animals">Animals</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Have you ever kept pets?<br>
I once had a poodle when I was in primary school. I named her Kuro, which means Black in Japanese. She was only six months old when it joined our family. Unfortunately, we had to send her away after a few weeks, because we noticed my mom getting allergic reactions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like to go to the zoo?<br>
I really like to go to the zoo, because I get to see rare animals that people don’t often see in their daily lives. It’s awesome to see different animals that I’ve never seen before, and every time I go to the zoo, I realize that there’s way more animals in this world than I imagined.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever seen any wild animals before?<br>
I’ve seen a wild red fox when I was on a vacation with my mom to Canada. My mom and I were talking and taking a stroll that day, and we stopped talking and stood in shock when we saw the fox, casually walking past us on a street, only a few meters away.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What wild animals do you like most?<br>
I really like clouded leopards (云豹). Clouded leopards are medium sized cats that are beautiful and majestic. They don’t have strong roars like some of the big cats, which makes them cute at the same time.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="languages">Languages</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What languages can you speak?<br>
I speak Chinese and English. Chinese is my first language and English is my second language. I’ve been trying to learn a little Japanese by myself during the summer break, but I haven’t progressed much, because I don’t have a lot of Japanese friends to have conversations with.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think it is difficult to learn a new language?<br>
I think it’s not that difficult to learn a new language. The most important thing about learning a new language is to practice. I like to learn a new language by watching TV and having conversations with friends. It doesn’t matter if you can’t speak fluently yet, because mistakes help you grow faster.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Will you learn other languages in the future?<br>
I wish I could learn Japanese in the future. I’ve been checking out a lot of videos about the different cultures in Japan, and I wish to go to Japan on a vacation in the future. Learning Japanese before going on the trip would come in handy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Why do you learn English?<br>
I learn English because English has become the most spoken language on the planet, it has become a universal language. By learning English, I would be able to speak decent English with people from other countries without expressing my message incorrectly.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="voice">Voice</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Has your voice ever changed?<br>
My voice had changed quite hard as I grew up. My voice used to be pretty high pitched when I was young, but as I grew up, it started getting deeper and deeper. In the end, my voice turned quite deep, which is very different compared to my voice when I was young.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you enjoy recording your voice and listening to it?<br>
I don’t really listen to my voice in a recording, because it sounds a lot different to how I actually sound in real life. I find that voice recordings tend to make my voice go higher pitched, which sounds really cute, and I’m actually not really used to it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like your own voice?<br>
I really like my own voice. When I talk slowly with confidence, I think it gives an impression to people that I’m mature and thoughtful. I also like singing because I like my own voice; however, I never record my own singing because it sounds really weird in recordings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Does your voice sound similar to your parents?<br>
Surprisingly, my voice sounds nothing like my parents. My mom has a really high-pitched tone, while my dad has a mediocre voice that’s not really deep. My parents often joked that I didn’t sound like their kid back when I was in high school.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="concentration">Concentration</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>When do you need to be focused?<br>
Currently I need to focus on my university study. Since my major is visual arts, I need to spend most of the time on projects and homework. Concentration on study is my priority for these four years.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What many distract you when you are trying to stay focused?<br>
To be honest, too much chatting online with friends is distracting me when I am trying to stay focused on my school study. Wechat is a good communication tool for today’s young generation, however, I am trying to control the time I spend on it every day.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you do to help you concentrate?<br>
In order to keep my concentration on study, I usually shut down my cellphone or go to the library to study for a few hours. Besides, I often find a study room at school where no friends can find me. In this way, I can focus on my homework by myself.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is it difficult for you to stay focused on something?<br>
Yes. When there are so many friends chatting with me online or hanging out together, it is difficult for me to stay focused on my study. When I am captivated with my favourite animation, I cannot concentrate on my homework at home. In general, I have difficulty to stay focused on something for a long time.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="jeans">Jeans</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you wear jeans?<br>
Yes. I usually wear jeans when I hang out with my friends. We often go for hiking, dancing and seeing movies during our holidays. Wearing jeans is a kind of fashion trend for today’s young generation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How often do you wear jeans?<br>
I often wear jeans at weekends, especially every Saturday. Since Saturday is a leisure time for me to relax after a week’s study at school. During my vacations and holidays, I also like to wear jeans to go travel with my family.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like wearing jeans, why?<br>
I like wearing jeans because it shows my body figure perfectly. And it is also a fashion trend for our young generation. I also like wearing jeans because they’re stylish. Furthermore, they are always leading the trend of the casual wears.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Why do you think jeans are popular in China?<br>
In China, people like to wear jeans in all kinds of occasions, formal and informal, weekdays and weekends, indoors and outdoors. The other reason I think jeans are popular in China is because people from older to younger generations like to wear jeans no matter if it is in winter or in summer. And there are a lot of stores and shops selling jeans everywhere in China.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="haircut">Haircut</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>What’s your favourite hairstyle?<br>
My favourite hairstyle is short straight hair. Since I am living in Southern China, it is extremely hot in summer. And I sweat a lot when it is hot. So a short straight hair style is suitable and favourable to me.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How often do you have your hair cut?<br>
My short straight hair style helps me to avoid going to the barber, so I go much less than my friends. I only have my hair cut every two weeks. Since I am currently studying in the university, I do not have too much money and time to keep changing my hairstyle.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How much do you usually spend on your haircut?<br>
I usually spend only one hundred yuan a month for my haircut. Every two weeks, it costs me fifty yuan to go to barber. It is a reasonable price for a simple hair cut nowadays.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you often change your haircut?<br>
No. I am not keen on changing my hairstyle, especially as I am a student currently. I need to concentrate on my school study all the time so that I can find a good job after graduation. Then I will think about changing my haircut or hairstyle more often.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How long have you had your current haircut?<br>
I have had my current haircut for at least two years since I entered into the university. I would like to focus on the study instead of my appearance for the coming two years in the school. And this is also because the weather in Guangzhou is terribly hot in summer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever had an unhappy haircut?<br>
Yes. I remember that in the summer vacation during my high school I was unhappy with my haircut. I was going back to my hometown with my parents. Since it is in the countryside, it is really hard for me to find a good barber. So I had to accept what the only barber in the village had done to my hair.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like to have your hair cut?<br>
Yes. I do like to have my hair cut. But I do not like to change my hairstyle too often. My favourite hairstyle is the short straight hair, and I do not like to have my hair dyed into other colours.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="walking">Walking</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you walk a lot?<br>
I do not walk a lot because I am not very interested in outdoor activities. In fact, I enjoy indoor exercises, such as Yoga, Aerobics and table tennis. I would like to take a walk only if I have eaten too much at dinner.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you walk more often than in the past?<br>
No. Since I am studying visual arts in the university, I have less time to go out for a walk. A lot of projects and homework I have to work on not only in the day, but also at night. I spend a lot of time on shopping, chatting and studying online instead of any outdoor activities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think people will walk more or not in the future?<br>
I think more and more people will walk less in the future. With the development of AI and different kinds of apps in cellphones, people do not need to walk more to get what they want. They can order everything online, meeting and chatting with friends by video calls. AI will meet their needs for indoor and outdoor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where do you usually take a walk?<br>
I usually take a walk in the park near my home. The park is a small but clean place for people to spend their leisure time, especially for the older generation. I like to take a walk over there because my parents like to be with me while they take a walk after dinner.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="countryside">Countryside</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like to live in countryside in the future?<br>
Yes. Although I am currently living in the city, I still like would to move to the countryside someday when I have my own family. This is because I would like to have a bigger space and a clean and healthy living environment for my baby to grow.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What would you like to do in the countryside?<br>
Living in the countryside, I would like to farm my own vegetable in my backyard so that I can eat healthy foods planted by myself every day. And I would like to raise and walk a dog in the field instead of keeping it at home. The most important thing I would like to do in the countryside is to breathe the fresh air while I am doing exercises.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How long have you lived in countryside?<br>
To be honest, I have only lived in countryside for a few days. It was because I went to my hometown to see my cousin with my parents. When I saw the green field, beautiful flowers and the little hill behind our old house in the countryside, I was attracted by the peaceful, quiet and healthy living environment over there.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What’s the benefits of living in rural areas?<br>
Living in rural areas, you can breathe the fresh air, have a bigger living space and healthier food than living in the cities. Besides, you can also have a quiet and peaceful quality of life. Less people and less pollution are also the advantages of living in rural areas.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="scenery1-4-月新题">Scenery(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Is there good scenery in your hometown?<br>
Yes, of course. There are many famous tourist attractions in my hometown, such as the Canton Tower, Pearl River and Baiyun Mountain. But I have been to these places so many times that they are not as attractive to me anymore.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When you travel, do you like to live in hotels with scenic views?<br>
No, I don’t. Because the hotels with scenic views are usually very expensive. I can go to the scenery in the daytime even though it will take me a little time to get there. I think staying in expensive hotels is a high cost way to travel.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like to take pictures of good scenery with your smartphone? Why?<br>
I like to use my smartphone to take pictures. My Huawei P30 has incredible photography functions. While on the journey, I always use my Huawei cellphone to take pictures for my friends. All of them are always astonished by the good effects of the pictures.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is there good scenery in cities?<br>
It depends. I think a skyline of skyscrapers is good scenery which I appreciate. But some people don’t, they may consider natural landscape as the best kind of scenery.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="pen-and-pencil1-4-月新题">Pen and pencil(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you usually use pen and pencil?<br>
No, I seldom use pen or pencil because I like to use the computer to read and do my study. I think typing through the computer is more convenient.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Which do you use more often? Pen or pencil?<br>
Pen, of course. The cartridge of the pencil is so fragile that it often breaks off easily. However, pen is much more durable, even if you drop it to the ground many times, it still works.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When was the last time you bought a pen or pencil?<br>
I don’t remember actually. Now I have several pens on hand. All of them were given as a present in school activities. So, I haven’t bought a pen for long time.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you think if someone gives you a pen or pencil as a present?<br>
I think it is old-fashion way to give a pen or pencil as a present. If someone did that, I would accept it, but I wouldn’t be happy about that.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="spend-time-by-yourself1-4-月新题">Spend time by yourself(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like to be alone?<br>
I like to be alone. It seems to be a strange answer, but I truly like to be alone because I can do whatever I want. I can enjoy playing computer games and watching movies without being disturbed by others when I am alone.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When was the last time you were alone and what did you do then?<br>
Maybe last weekend. When I came back home, I found that my parents were out. So, I tidied up my room and turned on the TV to watch some TV programs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you always do when you are alone?<br>
I usually watch movies when I am alone. Because I think it makes me feel comfortable to turn off all of lights in my room and watch a nice movie. That is the way life should be.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How do you usually spend your time by yourself?<br>
Like I said above, when I am home alone, I like to watch movies. But on a nice day, I also enjoy reading a book or exercising outside.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="laugh1-4-月新题">Laugh(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Are you the kind of person who makes people laugh?<br>
No, I am not the kind of person who can amuse others. I find it difficult to find common topics to communicate with others. But I like to keep company with this kind of person!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like to watch movies or TV shows that make people laugh?<br>
Yes, I do. Often at the end of a long day or a long week, I am in need of a lot of rest. So, I often relax by watching comedies which relieve my anxiety and tiredness.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you usually make your friends laugh?<br>
No, I am not the kind of person who can amuse others. Some people can find humor in everything and share it freely. I do not have an outgoing personality.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think it is important to laugh with friends?<br>
Yes, I think it is important. If you don’t laugh with your friends, they may consider you to be unsociable and aloof.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="water-sports1-4-月新题">Water sports(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Are water sports popular in China?<br>
No, I don’t think so. I think many people don’t have a chance to play water sports in their hometown. On one hand, water sports are expensive in cities where they are available, on the other hand, not all cities have water sports.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you done any water sports?<br>
I have done some, but not many. When I travelled to Phuket Island, I played on a banana boat and snorkeled. They were really exciting and relaxing sports.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What water sports do you like doing?<br>
I like snorkeling, although I have not snorkeled many times. It is an easy way to explore the ocean and doesn’t require complex skills. All I need to do it is to wear the suit and snorkeling mask and use the breathing tube.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kind of water sports do you want to try?<br>
I want to try deep diving. Because compared to snorkeling, deep diving would let me go deeper and see more sea creatures, such as turtles and crabs. However, deep diving requires certain skills, which take time to practice.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="running1-4-月新题">Running(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like running?<br>
Yes, of course. Running is my favourite sport. I usually run 5 kilometers every day. It is a kind of aerobic exercise which can improve our cardiovascular health.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How often do you go for a run?<br>
Like I said earlier. I usually run for 5 kilometers every day. I like to go running first thing in the morning because I start the day feeling more relaxed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Where do you usually go running?<br>
I usually go to the university stadium to run. The stadium has a nice track and not many people use it in the morning. So, I usually go there.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think running is a good way to stay healthy?<br>
It has been proven that running is a kind of aerobic exercise which can improve our cardiovascular health. I enjoy running very much and I think it is a good way to relieve stress.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="arts1-4-月新题">Arts(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Is there any artwork on the wall in your room?<br>
Yes, I have an oil painting on the wall in my room. It depicts a beautiful scenery of Fuji Mountain which I have been to before.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever visited an art gallery?<br>
No. I haven’t. I am not good at art and don’t really have an interest in it, so I haven’t been to an art gallery before. But I like to listen to music. Thus, I have been to many concerts.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like art?<br>
No, I don’t. Compared to art, I like music more because music has a power of healing. Whenever I feel tired or anxious, I like to listen to some relaxing music.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="cake1-4-月新题">Cake(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you like eating cakes?<br>
Yes, of course I love eating cakes. Doesn’t everyone? My favourite is mixed fruit cake. But I don’t like to eat those cakes with lots of cream. I like the fruit and chocolate cakes more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever made cakes?<br>
No, I haven’t. I am not that kind of person who is good at baking things. So, I haven’t tried to make cakes and I don’t think I will make cakes in the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What desserts do Chinese people like?<br>
I think many people like to eat sweets because they are cheap and easy to buy. Sweets come in many flavours and can satisfy many people's tastes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like dessert?<br>
Yes. My favourite food is mixed fruit cake and chocolate cake. Although they are a high sugar and fatty food, I still can't help craving dessert every day.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="history1-4-月新题">History(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Did you like history when you were young?<br>
I liked history, but I disliked the history class. I think history is the most boring subject that I have ever taken. There is no skill to learn it. All that you need to do is to remember, remember and remember.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>When was the last time you read about history?<br>
I follow the topic of history in my Daily News App, so it will push me to read many interesting historical stories every day. It is very good App and I enjoy the history stories in it. The stories are brief, but I can get more information if I am interested.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Have you ever been to historical museum?<br>
Yes, I have been to many historical museums. The biggest one that I have been to is the Forbidden City. But I think the most interesting historical museum is the Xi’An Historical Museum because Xi 'An has a long history and many stories took place in Xi 'An. Many important people were born and lived there, as well.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="science-class1-4-月新题">Science class(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you think science classes are important?<br>
I think they are very important, especially for children. Science class can arouse students' curiosity and cultivate their ability to explore the unknown.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Did you have science class in primary school or high school?<br>
Yes, I did have science classes in primary school. Science class was always full of fun because the teacher would tell us many interesting facts about the natural world. She always presented the information in an engaging way.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you like science class?<br>
Yes, I like it very much. Science class is always interesting because I enjoy thinking about science and nature. I think my primary school teacher encouraged me to want to learn more.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What kind of science did you do at school?<br>
Actually, I don’t remember exactly what I have learned in science classes in primary school, but I remember they were fun. In high school, I particularly enjoyed my science class in Biology.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="break-1-4-月新题">Break (1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>How often do you take a break?<br>
I usually take a ten-minute break once every hour from whatever work I am doing. It is very essential for me so I can unwind and refocus on my task again.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Why do you need to take a break?<br>
I think people need to take a break to relax so that they can recharge and focus on their task at hand again. Otherwise, they may feel tired and run out of energy. In a way, taking breaks enhance people’s working efficiency.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What do you usually do during a break?<br>
I usually close my eyes to relax or l go out to breathe some fresh air. Sometimes, I will get myself a cup of tea or coffee.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you prefer long break or several short breaks?<br>
I prefer one long break than several short breaks. Because several short breaks can easily distract people from staying focused on one thing. With long breaks, I can concentrate on my task to avoid making mistakes.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="number1-4-月新题">Number(1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Are you good at math?<br>
I think I am quite good at math. Math is my favourite subject and I spend a lot time studying it. Among all of the aspects of Math, I am very skillful at finding the solutions to geometric problems.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you usually use numbers?<br>
I usually use numbers in my day to day life. Everything we do in our lives normally requires a little bit of math and numbers. So, mathematics plays an important role in the real world and I think it is the one of the most useful subjects.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Are you good at remembering phone numbers?<br>
I have to say I am not good at remembering phone numbers. I only remember the phone numbers of my parents and my boyfriend. This is because I usually use WeChat to video call my friends, so there is no need for me to remember their phone numbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What ‘s your favourite number?<br>
It must be 14. It was my student ID from my primary school to high school. It is very amazing that this was my number as my student for so many years, because the students IDs are usually given to students by the rank of their entrance exam scores.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="park-1-4-月新题">Park (1-4 月新题)</h1>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Do you prefer natural parks or amusement parks?<br>
I prefer natural parks. I love the feeling of peace and calm that I can find at a natural park. Though there are tons of fun things to do in an amusement park, I would be happier to take a walk in a forest or beside a lake.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you think people like going to parks?<br>
There isn’t much open space in the city, all the buildings are close together and living spaces are tight. A park is a brilliant place to escape these things and it can help people unwind and relax.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What activities can be done in a park?<br>
There are many activities that can be done in a park, such as playing badminton or football. But Chinese people especially like to do square dancing in the park. When the night falls, many retired people go to the parks, turn on the radio and start to square dance with the rhythm of music.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do you often go to a park?<br>
Not very often. However, whenever I feel anxious or something bad happens, I will go to the park to unwind. A park is a perfect place to escape the hustle and bustle of the city and the things that annoy me.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#读书笔记#  Everything I never told you]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/EtcOEBUBX</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/EtcOEBUBX">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-01-09T07:14:34.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>必须要承认，我一直都不是书虫类型的人，以前看书大部分是为了考试，其余的，顶多也就是看一些畅销书，消磨时光罢了。未曾想，随着年龄越来越大，竟然慢慢可以从看书中找寻到一直渴望的内心的平静。陆陆续续的，也看了一些书，看的时候，思绪万千，想到了很多，可是人又是那么的健忘，看完之后，很快便忘了七七八八。所以，在2020年的伊始，立一个flag，每个月至少写一篇书评吧（以后打脸了再说），就算是记录一下自己的成长。希望一年，或者两年后回看，能够感受到自己的时光没有白白流逝，而是转化为文字，记录了下来，即使一开始如同中学生作文那般稚嫩。</p>
<p>其实这本书我在2019年12月就已经看完了，但是迟迟不敢下笔写书评，或许是恐惧吧，毕竟已经那么长时间不曾正儿八经地输出自己的想法，怕没什么可写的，也怕写的乱七八糟，不像样子。就是鸵鸟一样，藏着，假装这样别人就不知道我的浅薄了。后来发现自己想的太多了，互联网上的内容那么多，又有多少人会注意到我；人们都是那么得忙，谁会管我的文字是否成熟。这样安慰过自己以后，就释然了，不再战战兢兢的，决定提笔写写自己的想法。</p>
<p>一开始看这本书纯属偶然，不过是一本学习英语的app送的，拿到手以后看着封面挺有趣的，就打开了。看之前完全不知道到底是什么类型的，梗概是什么，后来发现，这样也好，刚好可以检验一下是否这本书对我的胃口。实践出真知，我并不喜欢，尽管这本书在2014年荣获亚马逊Best Book的第一。</p>
<p>这本书以一个小姑娘莉迪亚的死展开，然后抽丝剥茧式的，分析一个普通却又不普通的美国家庭中存在的问题， 聊到了，教育，婚姻，种族。说它普通，是因为其实并没有什么轰轰烈烈又转折的情节，除了一开始的“案件”给了一些悬疑的背景，可是后来发现这个“案件”竟是意外而已；说它不普通，因为故事的背景设置在上世纪七十年代，美国中部俄亥俄州的一个小镇，而且这个家庭是种族通婚。莉迪亚的母亲是一个漂亮又平凡的美国白人，父亲詹姆斯是中国的二代移民。 放在现代可能不怎么会吸引人的目光了，但是美国的最高法院于1967年才通过了反异族通婚法，在此之前，不同种族之间结婚是违反法律的行为，因此，这个跨种族的结合才显得那么的不同。</p>
<p>这本书涉及到的可聊的内容还是蛮多的，但是其中最触动我的是两个，一个是詹姆斯那么执着的想要的“融入”，另一个是玛丽琳对女儿的“爱”。他们两个把自己的期许，不加掩饰地压在了莉迪亚的身上，当然也采用了父母最常用的说法—为了你好，如此沉甸甸，像两个又浓又密的翅膀，莉迪亚被包裹在里面，挣扎不得，直到最后窒息在其中。私以为这种爱最为无耻且自私，将下一代作为自己希望的延续却不曾想过自己的下一代首先是要有完整的独立人格存在于世，自己的爱好，自己的想法，自己的未来。继而联想到曾经看到过的一段话，若是父母在生我之前可以问我一下，我坚决选择不要来到这个世上。这句话，引起了我强烈的共鸣，尤其是最近这几个月，我越来越绝望，对这个社会，找不到自己存在的意义。</p>
<p>所谓融入<em>so-called blend in</em><br>
在本书中，詹姆斯一直想要可以真正地融入到美国主流环境，其源头来自于他的童年经历，虽出生且生长在美国，但是却从未被当成过是“美国人”，主要还是因为他的肤色，总是可以让他显得那么的与众不同，当然不是正面的不同。在上学的时候，他是学校里唯一的一个亚裔，他所有的一切都会引起其他人的好奇。他在研究着学业而他的同学们在研究着他，他的瞳孔的颜色。或许他的同学真的只是好奇而已，但是却给年幼的他带来了心理上的阴影。若是他可以明白，那真的不是他的肤色带来的问题，多好。因为，很有可能，其他的小伙伴们研究他是像研究没有见过的物品一样，记得在我小时候，我那四十八线的小村庄来了一个外国人采风，结果差不多半个村子的人都快要围上去了，都想看看那个金发碧眼的外国人。我不感觉当时围上去的人全都是有恶意的，估计他们也不知道自己的举动会不会影响到别人。</p>
<p>詹姆斯在哈佛教学的时候，他所教的科目是<em>The cowboy in American culture</em>.第一节课上，在看到授课老师竟然是一个其貌不扬且瘦弱的亚裔以后，大部分的学生立刻选择了换课，其中还有当着他的面走出教室的。我想，他们应该都会感觉这是一个笑话，一个亚裔，来教美国文化。最有趣的是，玛丽琳一开始震惊与詹姆斯的英语如此之好，竟然都没有口音。当然后来，她也是被这个东方男人的“不同”给吸引到的。这里，我不能说这些学生没有恶意，他们只是没有脑子罢了。可是这些事，脱去种族的外衣，依然存在，就像我来自一个村到不能再村的地方，很多人会以为我的英语会带着极强的地方特色，有的时候，也会想要看我的笑话。</p>
<p>詹姆斯极力摆脱着肤色的不同给他带来的心理上的烙印，甚至来说，他厌恶自己的肤色带来的一系列不同。在学校读书的时候，他拒绝父母接送他，这样同学们就不会看到他的父母。他不会读写中文，当然内心也十分抗拒去学。同时，他拒绝吃中餐，宁愿吃一直被中国留学生吐槽的难吃到极点的冷三明治。在学校里，他不选跟亚洲或者亚洲文化有关的课程，而选择基本跟东方毫无联系的的—<em>cowboy</em>。无非，就是想要别人认为他是一个“美国人”罢了。作为社会中的一员，想要“融入，”基本上可以算是一种本能反应了。我们到了一个新的环境，总是会不自觉的想要去找跟我们有相同或者类似经历的小伙伴，性别，家乡，爱好，等等。好像这样，我们就不会感到孤单。这样的融入，会给我们带来什么什么好处呢？内心上的安全感？朋友？资源？关系网？</p>
<p>而一个人到底能不能融入，感受会受到内外和外在的双重影响，有些人自己本身就不爱跟别人交流，或者性格上的孤僻不是大众喜爱的那个类型，有的或许是周围环境的问题，并不一定是自己不愿踏出那一步。可是，我想问的是，扪心自问一下，难道我们自己就很“融入”自己目前所在的环境中吗？即使没有受到文化，种族这些问题的影响。摸摸我的良心，我感觉不是的，从小时候到现在，一直都不是什么受欢迎那种类型的人，没有什么朋友，一直都感觉自己像是游走在群体的边缘，我不理解他们，他们也不理解我。所以，我个人感觉，即使在相同的肤色，文化中，依然会存在无法融入的问题。在本书中，玛丽琳就是很好的例子，即使身为美国白人，她依然面临着同样的问题，没有什么朋友，无法做到所谓的融入。当然她没有经历过别人研究她的瞳孔颜色这么荒谬的事儿，但是不代表她没有经历过别的研究。</p>
<p>那么如果不能融入，又该如何呢？感觉这个，会像是一个自我救赎的过程。诚然，人乃群居性动物，但是我认为也要认识到，有的时候，不能融入，没有关系，重要的是要明白其实就算是所谓那个“圈子”里的人，也不见得快乐，不见得能够解决掉所有的问题，重要的还是自己的内心强大。就像为什么被研究的詹姆斯会非常敏感，而我的小镇上出现过的那个外国人应该不会有呢？的确，我没有问过那个外国人本人，但是有问过有相同经历的外国人。他们给我的回复是，感觉哪些村民们很有趣—没有见过世面的有趣。那么反过来想，当时研究詹姆斯的人，不也是这样的吗？</p>
<p>亲密暴力<em>IPV-intimate partner violence</em><br>
这个词是我在看完书以后才接触到的，它的意思是现任或前任配偶或伴侣针对另一位配偶或伴侣的亲密关系中的家庭暴力。其形式有多种，身体，言语，精神，经济和性虐待。如果单单根据定义，感觉把玛丽琳的“爱”定义为亲密暴力似乎不妥，但是再仔细琢磨一下，感觉也算属于其中。玛丽琳利用了女儿对她的爱从而达到了操控女儿的目的。</p>
<p>所有的一开始起源于玛丽琳想要回到自己曾经为自己定下的那个人生轨迹中去，上医学院，然后成为一名医生。然而她的行程断在了遇到了詹姆斯，怀孕，辍学。在母亲去世时，她去整理遗物，不经意间翻到了母亲的那本食谱，翻着翻着，突然感觉母亲的一生，留下的印迹似乎不过是如何做好饭，这个想法使她震惊，因为现在的她，正在同样的道路上。然后她像被闪电劈了一样，不断地告诉自己，“<em>I will never end up like that</em>”。然后，在辍学多年后，她决定重新开始自己中断的学业。</p>
<p>我非常欣赏她的勇气和想法，但是确实完全无法理解她的做法。因为她几乎是完全抛弃了剩下的父子三人，独自离开了家。可能在我幼稚的想法里，她可以先考虑跟詹姆斯聊聊，虽然很有可能詹姆斯不支持，不理解，但是至少可以让他知道你的想法。或者实在是理念上不同了，离婚再开始。完全没有必要让他们有那种悬着的感觉。当然最后玛丽琳还是没有回到她想要的轨迹上，因为她又怀孕了。而她这次非常自私且不负责任的做法给自己的孩子们，尤其是莉迪亚造成了极大的恐惧。莉迪亚太害怕回再次失去母亲了，于是从这次事件以后，便对母亲说的所有都说yes.而玛丽琳，彻彻底底得利用了女儿对她的爱，利用了女儿不过是想要一个母亲的渴望。</p>
<p>可是，如果玛丽琳一开始可以想通，自己的生活是自己的，但是女儿也有属于女儿自己的生活，而不是完全把自己的想法强加到莉迪亚身上，是不是就不会有后面悲剧的发生。她是如此的自私，利用，裹挟着女儿的懂事，肆意挥霍着女儿对她的爱，直到最后女儿再也无法承受这份爱。书的最后，她看到了女儿偷偷留下了她以为自己已经扔掉的那本食谱，发现了女儿全部是因为爱她才答应了她所有的要求。在那个时候，我这个旁观者，多么的希望这个懂事的孩子可以像其她的青春期的女孩子那样，叛逆一下，不要那么听父母的话，多好。</p>
<p>看书的时候，想起了有一段时间，网上炒的沸沸扬扬的关于papi酱人生重要人物顺序的那个问题，我个人完全同意papi的想法，一个人连自我的都没有的时候，谈何爱其他人，即使爱，说不定也是带着私欲的爱。如果没有了自我，全部都是为了别人，那么你存在的意义，到底是什么？？多么希望父母可以不要把自己的孩子作为自己的私有财产，不要那么的随意控制，胁迫他们选择自己的人生道路。而孩子们，争点气，不要被别人胁迫，好吗？</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[# 雅思# 2020年1-4月雅思口语话题part 2&3]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/2W7MJgoSe</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/2W7MJgoSe">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-01-05T09:37:39.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>注：非原创，广大试水烤鸭们的成果，有需要的自取即可。<br>
加油！～ 最可爱的烤鸭们～～</p>
<h1 id="新题">新题</h1>
<h2 id="事件类">事件类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-an-important-flight-that-was-delayed">Describe an important flight that was delayed</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When it was<br>
Why it was important<br>
How it was delayed<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do people still drive a car if public transportation is free of charge?<br>
How can transportation in rural areas be developed?<br>
How do people usually go travelling<br>
In what wavs can traffic condition in a city be Improved?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-performance-that-you-watched-recently">Describe a performance that you watched recently</h3>
<p>You should say What it was<br>
When you watched it<br>
Who you were with<br>
And explain why you watched it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What's the difference between watching performance live and watching it on TV?<br>
Which do you prefer? Traditional performance or concert?<br>
Should government provide financial support to promote traditional performance?<br>
Is learning drama or dancing helpful for children?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-experience-that-others-apologised-to-you">Describe an experience that others apologised to you</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When it was<br>
Who this person is<br>
Why he or she apologised to you<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
On what occasion do people usually apologise to others?<br>
Do people in your country like to say &quot;sorry&quot;?<br>
Do you think people should apologise for anything wrong they do?<br>
Why do some people refuse to say &quot;sorry&quot; to others?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-experience-that-weather-prevented-your-activity">Describe an experience that weather prevented your activity</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When it was<br>
Why it prevented your activity<br>
What you did<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Does weather have any impact on people’s daily activities?<br>
Why do people do different kinds of sports in different weather?<br>
What kind of weather do Chinese people like?<br>
Do Chinese people talk about the weather when they meet for the first time?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-when-you-were-excited">Describe a time when you were excited</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
where you were<br>
when it was<br>
who you were with<br>
And explain why you were excited</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What personal events do people usually celebrate?<br>
How do people celebrate their personal events?<br>
How much time do people need to prepare for the celebration?<br>
Do you think it is necessary to spend some money on celebrations?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-piece-of-important-news-you-get-from-text-message">Describe a piece of important news you get from text message</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it was<br>
When you got it<br>
Who you got it from<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do you think traditional letters are a good way to send messages?<br>
Why do people make phone calls instead of sending messages when there is something important?<br>
Is it more polite to make phone calls than send text messages?<br>
Does technological development have a negative impact on communication among people?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-you-helped-others">Describe a time you helped others</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
Where you helped him or her<br>
Why you helped<br>
How you helped<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Should parents help their kids with their homework?<br>
What kind of advice should parents give to their children?<br>
Should parents give children advice? Why?<br>
Can kid provide any help to parents?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-new-skill-you-learnt-that-you-think-is-important">Describe a new skill you learnt that you think is important</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it is<br>
Whether it is difficult or not<br>
How you learned it<br>
And explain why you think it is important</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What skills are important for the success of business?<br>
What is the difference between required skills in the past and those at present?<br>
What kinds of skills should successful people have?<br>
Do you think teamwork and communication skills are important? Why?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-difficult-challenge-you-met">Describe a difficult challenge you met</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it was<br>
When you met it<br>
Where you met it<br>
And explain why you think it is a challenge</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do you think parents should give kids challenges?<br>
What challenges do you think children might have to face up to?<br>
What is the most challenging thing for kids?<br>
Can parents reduce the challenges that kids have? Why?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-you-were-not-allowed-to-use-your-mobile-phone">Describe a time you were not allowed to use your mobile phone</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When it was<br>
Where it was<br>
Why you could not use your mobile phone<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do you think it is necessary to have laws on the use of mobile phones?<br>
How do you like children having mobile phones?<br>
At what age should children have mobile phones?<br>
Are people politer now than in the past?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-team-where-you-were-a-member">Describe a team where you were a member</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it was like<br>
Why you joined it<br>
What you did in it<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Which one do you think is more important individual development or teams’ goals?<br>
Do you think it is a good thing to have disagreements within a team?<br>
Do you think it is good for kids to join a team?<br>
How to become a good member of a team in the workplace</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-trip-that-you-went-on-by-public-transportation">Describe a trip that you went on by public transportation</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
when and where you went<br>
what kind of transport you used<br>
what you did or saw on the trip<br>
how was your trip</p>
<p>Part 3</p>
<h2 id="地点类">地点类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-an-ideal-house-or-apartment-you-would-like-to-live-in-the-future">Describe an ideal house or apartment you would like to live in the future</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
Where it is<br>
What it is like<br>
Who you like to live there with<br>
And explain why you think it is ideal</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Where do people in China like to live, in a house or an apartment?<br>
What are the benefits of living in a house?<br>
Why do many people nowadays like to live in the city?<br>
Where do people like to live? In the city center or the suburbs?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-successful-small-company">Describe a successful small company</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it is<br>
What it is like<br>
How you know it<br>
How it becomes successful<br>
How you feel about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Which do you prefer, family firms or non-family ones?<br>
What are the important factors in making a company successful?<br>
What kinds of qualities should a successful businessman have?<br>
What emerging industries do you know?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-you-went-to-a-crowded-place">Describe a time you went to a crowded place</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
When you went there<br>
Where the place was<br>
What you did there<br>
And explain why you went there/how you felt the crowded place</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do people like to go to crowded places? Why?<br>
How can the problem of traffic congestion be solved?<br>
Why do people still like to live in big cities even though there are severe traffic jams?<br>
What public facilities does your city have?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-change-that-can-improve-your-local-area">Describe a change that can improve your local area</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it is<br>
How it can be made<br>
what problem it might bring<br>
And how you feel about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Why are people living in a community-friendly with others?<br>
What are the popular activities in a community?<br>
Do people like living in a community?<br>
Where do people in a community usually have a social gathering?</p>
<h2 id="人物类">人物类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-a-person-who-taught-you-something-important">Describe a person who taught you something important.</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
who this person was;<br>
what he or she taught you;<br>
how this person taught you;<br>
and explain why it was important to you.</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What qualities do you think a good teacher should have?<br>
Who do you think can learn better? Old people or youngsters?<br>
What do you think is the best age for children o go to school?<br>
Do you prefer to study by yourself or with your friends?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-person-you-know-from-the-news-that-you-want-to-meet">Describe a person you know from the news that you want to meet.</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Who this person is<br>
Where you knew him/her<br>
What he/she is like<br>
And explain why you want to meet him/her</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kind of people do you usually see in the news?<br>
Are stories about celebrities in the news always true?<br>
Is news often about famous people? Why?<br>
Could superstar bring positive influence to the public?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-family-member-who-youve-spent-the-most-time-with">Describe a family member who you've spent the most time with.</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
who this person is;<br>
what kind of person he or she is;<br>
what you usually do together;<br>
why you spend the most time together;<br>
and explain how you feel about being with him or her.</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What are the benefits of younger and older generations living together? How about the drawbacks?<br>
Which do you prefer: support from family members or friends? Why?<br>
How many generations does each family have?<br>
Is it important to visit family members? why?</p>
<h2 id="物品类">物品类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-an-article-online-or-in-a-magazine-which-helps-people-to-be-healthy">Describe an article online or in a magazine which helps people to be healthy</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it was<br>
Where you read it<br>
Why you read it<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What can governments do to improve people's health?<br>
What activities can school organise for children to keep fit?<br>
How can you tell whether a website is reliable or not?<br>
Do you think people are healthier now than in the past?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-interesting-animal-you-once-saw">Describe an interesting animal you once saw</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it was<br>
Where you saw it<br>
What it did<br>
And why you think it was interesting</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How do you like taking care of animals?<br>
Do you think it is safe for animals to live in the cities?<br>
What problems will keeping pets bring?<br>
How are pets now different from those in the past?<br>
How do you like taking care of animals?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-job-you-would-not-like-to-do-in-the-future">Describe a job you would not like to do in the future</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it is<br>
Where you knew it from<br>
Is it difficult or easy<br>
And explain why you would not like to do it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kind of job do young people prefer?<br>
Which do you prefer, physical work or mental work?<br>
What factors should people take into consideration when choosing jobs?<br>
Do people nowadays like to leave their hometowns to work in other cities? why?</p>
<h3 id="describe-something-you-bought-that-is-difficult-to-use-at-first">Describe something you bought that is difficult to use at first</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
What it was<br>
Where you bought it<br>
Why it was difficult to use<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kinds of products do young people think are useful but old people may not?<br>
Do you think product instructions are useful for users to use products better?<br>
What do you usually do if you do not know how to use things you have bought?<br>
Do you think it is necessary to produce many new products nowadays?</p>
<h1 id="旧题">旧题</h1>
<h2 id="事件类-2">事件类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-a-situation-when-you-celebrated-your-achievement">Describe a situation when you celebrated your achievement</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What you did<br>
When you celebrated it<br>
Who you celebrated it with<br>
And explain how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How do Chinese people celebrate their family events?<br>
Is there anything different from other countries?<br>
Why is it important for sports fans to celebrate when their favourite team wins?<br>
Do people prefer winning in a team or on their own?<br>
How are birthday celebrations different between you and the old?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-free-day-when-you-did-not-need-to-study-or-work">Describe a free day when you did not need to study or work</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
When it was<br>
What you did<br>
Who you were with<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do people have more free time than those in the past?<br>
What do people like to do when they are free in your country?<br>
Do you think most people are able to manage their free time?<br>
What is the difference between the things people do in their free time in the past and the things they do nowadays?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-when-you-first-met-someone">Describe a time when you first met someone</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where you met him or her<br>
When you met him or her<br>
What you talked about<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How do companies welcome their new employees?<br>
Do you think it is strange to make friends online?<br>
Why do some people have few friends<br>
Which is more important, new friendships or old ones?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-experience-that-you-got-bored-when-you-were-with-others">Describe an experience that you got bored when you were with others</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When it was<br>
Who you were with<br>
What you did<br>
And explain why you were bored</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Why do people get bored?<br>
Why are people less interested in reading books nowadays?<br>
Are all boring jobs going to be done by robots in the future?<br>
Why do some people choose boring jobs?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-special-day-that-you-remember-well">Describe a special day that you remember well</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where you were<br>
Who you were with<br>
What you did<br>
And explain why you remember it well</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do people spend too much money on their birthday party and wedding?<br>
How much should people spend their birthday party and a wedding?<br>
Which is the better way to retain memories, by videos or photos?<br>
How can forgetful people remember things better?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-you-were-sleepy-but-had-to-stay-awake">Describe a time you were sleepy but had to stay awake</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
When it happened<br>
Why you were sleepy<br>
Why you had to stay awake<br>
And explain why you stayed awake</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kind of people lack sleep?<br>
Why do people feel tired a lot nowadays?<br>
How do people keep awake when they are tired?<br>
What occasions do people need to keep awake even though they feel tired?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-leisure-activity-you-do-with-your-family">Describe a leisure activity you do with your family</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it is<br>
When you do it<br>
How you do it<br>
And explain how you feel about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What leisure activities are popular in China?<br>
What leisure activities do young people like?<br>
Do leisure activities have to be educational?<br>
Do men and women like different leisure activities?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-time-you-did-not-tell-a-friend-the-truthyou-lied-to-a-friend">Describe a time you did not tell a friend the truth/you lied to a friend</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
When it was<br>
Where it happened<br>
Why you did not tell the truth<br>
And explain how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do you think mutual trust between friends is important?<br>
Do you think people need to tell the truth all the time?<br>
Why do children tell lies?<br>
What should parents do if their children tell lies?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-occasion-when-you-lost-something-and-then-got-it-back">Describe an occasion when you lost something and then got it back</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
what you lost How you lost it<br>
Where you found it<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Why do people lose their things?<br>
What kinds of things do people usually lose?<br>
What can people do to find things they have lost?<br>
What can people do to avoid losing their stuff?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-advice-you-received-on-your-subjects-or-work">Describe an advice you received on your subjects or work</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it was<br>
Who you received it from<br>
What you did after receiving it<br>
And explain how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Why do so many young people choose communication and media studies as their major?<br>
Why do young people find it hard to make career choices?<br>
What can affect the career choices of young people?<br>
Can people have free choices for their jobs?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-interesting-conversation-you-had-with-someone">Describe an interesting conversation you had with someone</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Who this person is<br>
What the conversation was about<br>
Why you had this conversation<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What do men like to talk about? How about women?<br>
What is the difference between face-to-face communication and phone calls?<br>
Why are some people nervous when making a presentation?<br>
Is it appropriate to make some jokes during a presentation?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-special-day-that-made-you-happy">Describe a special day that made you happy</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
Where you were<br>
Who you were with<br>
What you did<br>
And explain why it made you happy</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Are modern people happier than those living in the past?<br>
Who do you like to have celebrations with? Friends or families?<br>
Can money make people happy?<br>
Why are some people unhappy nowadays?</p>
<h3 id="describe-an-experience-that-you-played-an-indoor-game-with-others">Describe an experience that you played an indoor game with others</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What you played<br>
Who you played it with<br>
Why you played it<br>
And explain how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Is teamwork important to individuals?<br>
what qualities should team leaders have?<br>
What indoor games do children like to play nowadays?<br>
What do you think of people spending too much time playing computer games?</p>
<h2 id="地点类-2">地点类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-a-place-you-remember-well-that-is-full-of-colours">Describe a place you remember well that is full of colours</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where it is<br>
What it is like<br>
What it is used for<br>
And explain why you remember it well</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Is colour important for clothing?<br>
Should course books be colourful?<br>
What colour do you think people would choose when decorating their houses?<br>
Do you think the colour of a company’s uniform represents the image of the company?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-place-not-your-home-where-you-read-and-write">Describe a place (not your home) where you read and write</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where it is<br>
How often you go there<br>
Who you go there with<br>
And explain how you feel about this place</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What do you think is more important? is more important, reading or writing?<br>
Who needs to have good writing skills?<br>
Where can people get more information, words or pictures?<br>
At what age should children start to read?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-school-you-went-to-in-your-childhood">Describe a school you went to in your childhood</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where it was<br>
what it was like<br>
what you learned there<br>
and how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What is the difference between the present and the past teachers?<br>
What is the difference between being taught by teachers and being taught by AI?<br>
What is the difference between private schools and public schools?<br>
What is the difference between international schools and other schools?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-new-public-building-you-would-like-to-visit">Describe a new public building you would like to visit</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
where it is<br>
what it is like<br>
how you knew this place<br>
and why you would like to visit it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Do you think the appearance of a building is important?<br>
Which is more important? Preserving old buildings or building new ones?<br>
What kinds of public buildings do people like to visit in China?<br>
What is most important to a public building? Design, location or facilities?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-beautiful-sky-you-enjoyed-seeing">Describe a beautiful sky you enjoyed seeing</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where you saw it<br>
Who you saw it with<br>
What you saw<br>
And how you felt about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kind of people are interested in the stars?<br>
Should kids know more about stars and planets?<br>
Is high technology helpful for star watching?<br>
Why do some people like to watch movies about stars or plants?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-historical-building-you-have-been-to">Describe a historical building you have been to</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where it is<br>
What it looks like<br>
What it is used for now<br>
What you learned there<br>
And how you felt about this historical building</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
Is it necessary to protect historical buildings?<br>
Why do people visit historical buildings?<br>
Do Chinese people like to visit historical buildings?</p>
<h2 id="人物类-2">人物类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-a-person-who-is-good-at-his-or-her-job">Describe a person who is good at his or her job</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
Who this person is<br>
What his or her job is<br>
How he or she likes the job<br>
And explain why this person is good at the job</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How can people improve their job performance?<br>
What skillset should a manager have?<br>
Do you think what you learn in university is going to help in your future job?<br>
How should young people perform on their first job?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-person-who-often-travels-by-plane">Describe a person who often travels by plane</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Who he or she is<br>
Where he or she goes<br>
Why he or she travels by plane<br>
And explain how he or she feels about it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What are the advantages of traveling by plane?<br>
Why do some people prefer to travel by train?<br>
What are the disadvantages of living near an airport?<br>
How is working at the airport different from working in other places?</p>
<h2 id="物品类-2">物品类</h2>
<h3 id="describe-a-film-you-would-like-to-share-with-your-friends">Describe a film you would like to share with your friends</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
Where you watched it<br>
What it was about<br>
Who you watched it with<br>
And explain why you want to share it with friends</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kind of film is popular in China?<br>
What kinds of films do young people like to watch?<br>
Do fewer people choose to watch movies in the cinema than people did in the past?<br>
Do you think cinemas will disappear in the future?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-gift-that-took-you-a-lot-of-time-to-prepare">Describe a gift that took you a lot of time to prepare</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it is<br>
Who you gave it to<br>
How you prepared it<br>
And explain why you spend a lot of time preparing it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How do people usually choose gifts?<br>
Why do some people find it hard to choose gifts?<br>
Do you think useful gifts are always more suitable than those useless ones?<br>
Do people give the same gifts as they did in the past?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-picture-or-photograph-you-like-in-your-room">Describe a picture or photograph you like in your room</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What is in it<br>
Where it is How you got it<br>
And explain why you like it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What are the advantages and disadvantages of taking photos with smartphones?<br>
Do you think photographers are artists?<br>
What are the benefits of learning painting for children?<br>
Can anyone become a famous artist through hard work?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-popular-product-eg-food-handicraft-made-in-your-region">Describe a popular product (e.g. food, handicraft…) made in your region</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it is<br>
What it is like<br>
How it is made<br>
And explain why it is popular</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What food is popular throughout the world?<br>
Why do people use imported products?<br>
Why do people living in different regions like different food?<br>
Do places have their own popular products?</p>
<h3 id="describe-something-useful-you-borrowed-from-others">Describe something useful you borrowed from others</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
What it was<br>
When you borrowed it<br>
Who you borrowed it from<br>
And explain why you borrowed it</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
What kinds of things do people borrow from each other?<br>
What other things that people don't choose to lend to others?<br>
Do we always need to get permissions from others before using something they have? What do you think of copying ideas from others?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-toy-that-you-played-in-your-childhood">Describe a toy that you played in your childhood</h3>
<p>You should say:<br>
When you had the toy<br>
Who gave you the toy<br>
What it was like<br>
How you felt about the toy</p>
<p>Part 3<br>
How do advertisements influence children?<br>
Should advertising aiming at kids be prohibited?<br>
Do you think parents should buy more toys for their kids or spend more time with them?<br>
What’s the difference between the toys kids play now and those they play in the past?</p>
<h3 id="describe-a-uniform-in-school-or-company-you-wear">Describe a uniform (in school or company) you wear</h3>
<p>You should say<br>
When you usually wear it<br>
Who bought it for you<br>
What it is like<br>
And how you feel about it<br>
Part 3<br>
Why should students wear school uniforms?<br>
On what occasion should people wear uniforms?<br>
Should companies ask for employees' opinions about the design of uniforms?<br>
Can people tell a person's personality by his/her clothes?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[# 雅思# 2020年1-4月雅思口语话题part 1 ]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/ZN6ZF1pzl</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/ZN6ZF1pzl">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-01-05T09:14:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>注：非原创，广大试水烤鸭们的成果，有需要的自取即可。<br>
加油！～ 最可爱的烤鸭们～～</p>
<h1 id="新题">新题</h1>
<h2 id="art">Art</h2>
<p>Do you like art?<br>
Did you have art classes when you were at school?<br>
Have you ever visited an art gallery?<br>
Do you often visit art galleries?<br>
Is there any artwork on the wall in your room?</p>
<h2 id="break-time">Break time</h2>
<p>Do you prefer to work/study in the morning or afternoon?<br>
Do you prefer short breaks or long breaks?<br>
What do you do during breaks?<br>
Why do people need to take breaks?</p>
<h2 id="being-alone">Being alone</h2>
<p>Do you like to be alone?<br>
What was the last time when you were alone and what did you do then?<br>
What do you always do when you are alone?</p>
<h2 id="dessert">Dessert</h2>
<p>Do you like dessert?<br>
Do you like eating cakes?<br>
Have you ever made cake?<br>
Special cake in your country?</p>
<h2 id="history">History</h2>
<p>Do you like history?<br>
When you were a child, did you enjoy learning history?<br>
Have you ever been to a museum to learn about history?<br>
Have you ever watched movies related to history?<br>
When was the last time you read a book about history?<br>
Do you think history is important?</p>
<h2 id="laugh">Laugh</h2>
<p>Do you like to watch movies or TV shows that make people laugh?<br>
Are you the kind of person who makes people laugh?<br>
Do you usually make your friends laugh?<br>
When was the last time you laughed? (Why?)<br>
Do you like to make people laugh?<br>
Do you like watching funny TV shows?<br>
Do you think it's important for friends to have the same sense of humour?<br>
Do you think it's important for friends to laugh together?</p>
<h2 id="number">Number</h2>
<p>Are you good at remembering phone numbers?<br>
Do you often use numbers to do something?<br>
Is there any special number you like?<br>
Do you have a favourite number?<br>
Are you good at numbers (maths)?<br>
Would you like to have a  job dealing with numbers?</p>
<h2 id="parks">Parks</h2>
<p>Do you often go to parks?<br>
What activities can be done in a park?<br>
Do you think people like going to parks?<br>
Do you prefer natural parks or amusement parks?</p>
<h2 id="pen-or-pencil">Pen or pencil</h2>
<p>Do you usually use pen or pencil?<br>
Which do you use more often? Pen or pencil?<br>
When was the last time you bought a pen or pencil?<br>
What do you think if someone gives you a pen or a pencil as a present?<br>
How would you feel if someone gave you a pen as s gift?<br>
Did your teachers teach you how to write with a pencil or pen?</p>
<h2 id="science-classes">Science classes</h2>
<p>Do you like science classes?<br>
Did you have science classes when you were in primary or middle school?<br>
Do you think these classes are helpful in your adult life?<br>
Do you read science magazines?<br>
Do you think science classes are important?</p>
<h2 id="sceneryview">Scenery/view</h2>
<p>Is there good scenery in your hometown?<br>
Is there good scenery in cities?<br>
When you travel, do you like to live in hotels with scenic views?<br>
Do you like to stay in places with beautiful views when you are traveling?<br>
Do you like to take pictures of good scenery with your smartphone? Why?<br>
Would you say people enjoy taking pictures of beautiful scenery?<br>
Can you suggest why some people use their mobile phone to take pictures of beautiful views?</p>
<h2 id="running">Running</h2>
<p>Do you like running?<br>
Do you think running is a good way to stay healthy?<br>
Where do you usually go running?<br>
How often do you go for a run?<br>
Have you ever run a long distance?<br>
Do schools organise running activities?<br>
Have you watched any running competitions?<br>
When was the last time you take for a long run, why?</p>
<h2 id="water-sports">Water sports</h2>
<p>Are water sports popular in china?<br>
What water sports do you like doing?<br>
Have you ever done water sports?<br>
What kind of water sports do you want to try?</p>
<h1 id="老题">老题</h1>
<h2 id="workstudy">Work/study</h2>
<p>Why did you choose to do that type of work (or, that job）？<br>
Do you miss being a student？<br>
Is it very interesting？<br>
Do you like your job？<br>
Why did you choose to study that subject? / Why did you choose to study those subjects？<br>
Is it very interesting？<br>
What subject (s) are you studying？<br>
Do you prefer to study in the mornings or the afternoons？<br>
Are you looking forward to working？<br>
Do you like your subject? (why/ why not？）</p>
<h2 id="the-area-you-live-in">The area you live in</h2>
<p>Do you like the area that you live in?<br>
What are some changes in the area recently?<br>
Do you know any famous people in your area?<br>
Where do you like to go in that area?</p>
<h2 id="your-accommodation">Your accommodation</h2>
<p>What kind of housing/ accommodation do you live in？<br>
Do you live in a house or a flat？<br>
What's the difference between where you are living now and where you have lived in the past？<br>
Can you describe the place where you live？<br>
Which room does your family spend most of the time in？<br>
How long have you lived there？<br>
What do you usually do in your house/fat/room?<br>
Do you plan to live there for a long time？<br>
Are the transport facilities to your home very good？<br>
Please describe the room you live in？<br>
Do you prefer living in a house or a flat？<br>
What part of your home do you like the most？</p>
<h2 id="countryside">Countryside</h2>
<p>Do you enjoy living in the countryside?<br>
Will you live in the countryside in the future?<br>
What do you usually do in the countryside?<br>
Have you ever lived in the countryside?</p>
<h2 id="concentration">Concentration</h2>
<p>What might distract you when you’re trying to stay focused?<br>
When do you need to be focused?<br>
Is it difficult for you to stay focused on sth?<br>
What do you do to help you concentrate?</p>
<h2 id="friends">Friends</h2>
<p>What kinds of people do you like to make friends with?<br>
What do you usually do when you are with your friends?<br>
Do you keep in contact with any of your friends from your childhood?<br>
What do you think makes a good friend?<br>
Would you say you are a good friend to others?<br>
Do you prefer to spend time with your family or with your friends?<br>
Which do you think is more important, your family or your friends?</p>
<h2 id="haircut">Haircut</h2>
<p>When was the last time you got a haircut?<br>
What hairstyle did you go for?<br>
How often do you change your hairstyle?<br>
Were you happy about the last haircut you got?</p>
<h2 id="jeans">Jeans</h2>
<p>How often do you wear jeans?<br>
Do you like wearing jeans?<br>
Why do you think jeans are popular?<br>
Do you think jeans will be more popular in the future?</p>
<h2 id="languages">Languages</h2>
<p>How many languages do you speak?<br>
Are you currently learning other languages?<br>
How did you learn the language you speak?<br>
Do you think English is hard to learn?</p>
<h2 id="music">Music</h2>
<p>When do you listen to music?<br>
What's your favourite type of music?<br>
Do you prefer to listen to music alone, or with others?<br>
Has your preference in music changed since you were younger?<br>
How much time do you spend listening to music every day?<br>
What kinds of music do you like to listen to?<br>
Have you ever been to a concert before?</p>
<h2 id="movie">Movie</h2>
<p>What is your favourite movie?<br>
Do your friends like this movie?<br>
What kinds of movies do you think young people like?<br>
Do you want to be a movie star?</p>
<h2 id="patience">Patience</h2>
<p>What do you think patience is?<br>
Do you think patience is important?<br>
Do you think you are a patient person?<br>
Have you ever lost your patience?<br>
Were you patient when you were young?<br>
How do you feel when other people are not patient?<br>
Were you less or more patient when you were angry?</p>
<h2 id="photos">Photos</h2>
<p>Do you like to take photos?<br>
Do you prefer to take photos yourself or to have other people take photos?<br>
How often do you take photos?<br>
In what situations do you take photos?<br>
How do you keep your photos?</p>
<h2 id="public-holiday">Public holiday</h2>
<p>How many public holidays do you have in China?<br>
Do you think people need more public holidays?<br>
HOW do you usually spend your holidays?<br>
Which holiday is your favourite?</p>
<h2 id="reading">Reading</h2>
<p>Do you like to read?<br>
What kind of books do you read?<br>
Do you read books about what you are studying?<br>
Do you read more often for study or for fun?<br>
Do you prefer reading e-books or paper books?</p>
<h2 id="travel">Travel</h2>
<p>Do you like travelling?<br>
Which cities have you travelled to?<br>
What kind of cities do you like to travel to?<br>
What is the place that left you the deepest impression when travelling?</p>
<h2 id="tea-or-coffee">Tea or coffee</h2>
<p>Do you often drink coffee or tea?<br>
When was the last time you drank tea or coffee?<br>
What do you usually prepare for your guests, tea or coffee?<br>
Do people in your country give others coffee or tea as a gift?<br>
Do Chinese people like to drink tea or coffee?</p>
<h2 id="voices">Voices</h2>
<p>Has your voice ever changed?<br>
Do you enjoy recording your voice and listening to it?<br>
Do you like your own voice?<br>
Does your voice sound familiar to your parents'?</p>
<h2 id="walking">Walking</h2>
<p>Do you walk a lot?<br>
Where do you usually take a walk?<br>
Do you think people will walk more or not in the future?<br>
Do you walk more often than in the past?</p>
<h2 id="wild-animals">Wild animals</h2>
<p>Have you ever kept pets?<br>
Do you like to go to the zoo?<br>
Have you ever seen any wild animals before?<br>
What wild animal do you like most?</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[##雅思# #口语# 常用原因&解释 -- 累]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/WxZg0r4zH</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/WxZg0r4zH">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-29T00:43:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>I'm tired.</strong><br>
不管是在原因中还是最新的一个话题中，都有对累的描述，我们需要积累不同的表达方式，这样才可以避免重复。<br>
当然，还需要注意好用法额～</p>
<p><strong>加副词来表示程度</strong><br>
<em>I'm very tired.</em><br>
<em>I'm kind of tired.</em><br>
<em>He is pretty tired.</em><br>
<em>I am unbelievably tired.</em><br>
<em>She is mentally tired.</em><br>
<em>We are physically tired.</em><br>
<em><strong>I'm dead tired.</strong></em><br>
<em><strong>I’m dog-tired.</strong></em><br>
<em><strong>I’m tired to the bone.</strong></em></p>
<h1 id="im-exhausted">I'm exhausted.</h1>
<p>The word &quot;exhausted&quot; means very tired.<br>
I am exhausted.<br>
<em>She felt exhausted after the game.</em></p>
<h1 id="im-beat">I'm beat.</h1>
<p>This is a common expression to say that we are tired. We only use this in casual situations.</p>
<h1 id="i-am-drained">I am drained.</h1>
<p>drain本身是排水的意思<br>
在这里的用法很形象，你被抽干了，那自然就很累了<br>
<em>We have been working so much. I am drained.</em><br>
<em>I feel drained after working all weekend.</em></p>
<p>draining  adj.<br>
同样的意思，但是主语不一样<br>
在这里主语应该是物<br>
causing you to lose most of your energy; very tiring<br>
<em>He found the funeral service emotionally draining.</em></p>
<h1 id="im-wiped-out">I'm wiped out.</h1>
<p>similar to &quot;I'm drained&quot;</p>
<h1 id="im-worn-out">I'm worn out.</h1>
<p>需要注意的是，这个短语用来表示在工作了很久以后很累<br>
<em>I have worked every day for the last 3 months. I'm worn out.</em><br>
<em>We have been so busy this week. I am worn out.</em><br>
<em>We also use the phrase &quot;worn out&quot; with clothes or things that we have used for a long long time and now their condition is not good.</em><br>
<em>I have been wearing these shoes for 2 years. They are worn out.</em></p>
<h1 id="im-burnt-out">I'm burnt out.</h1>
<p>This expression is only used to show that we are tired because of doing something over a long period of time. All of our energy has been used up. This expression has the feeling that we have lost our passion or desire to do something.<br>
<em>I have worked overtime every day for the past month. I am burnt out.</em><br>
<em>I think I need a vacation. I feel burnt out.</em><br>
<em>Remember that we cannot use this with short-term things.</em><br>
<em>I ran for an hour today. I am burnt out.</em><br>
<em>I ran for an hour today. I am exhausted.</em></p>
<h1 id="im-fried">I'm fried.</h1>
<p>It means that I am so tired, that my brain is fried. So, we are so tired that we cannot think well.</p>
<h1 id="im-spent">I'm spent.</h1>
<p>This means that we have spent all of our energy. Therefore, we feel tired.</p>
<h1 id="i-am-weary">I am weary.</h1>
<p>&quot;Weary&quot; is a more formal word that means tired. We are more likely to see this in books and writing.</p>
<h1 id="im-whacked">I’m whacked.</h1>
<h1 id="im-on-my-last-legs">I’m on my last legs.</h1>
<h1 id="im-bushed">I’m bushed.</h1>
<h1 id="im-knackered">I’m knackered.</h1>
<h1 id="im-flat-out-tired">I’m flat out tired.</h1>
<h1 id="im-dead-on-my-feet">I’m dead on my feet.</h1>
<h1 id="im-running-on-empty">I’m running on empty.</h1>
<p>#I’m running on fumes.</p>
<h1 id="im-tired-out">I’m tired out.</h1>
<h1 id="im-dragging">I’m dragging.</h1>
<h1 id="im-stuffed">I’m stuffed.</h1>
<h1 id="im-drowsy">I’m drowsy.</h1>
<h1 id="i-can-hardly-keep-my-eyes-open">I can hardly keep my eyes open.</h1>
<h1 id="im-off-to-bed">I’m off to bed.</h1>
<h1 id="im-gonna-hit-the-sack">I’m gonna hit the sack.</h1>
<h1 id="im-all-in">I’m all in</h1>
<h1 id="im-shattered">I’m shattered</h1>
<h1 id="im-dead-to-the-world">I’m dead to the world</h1>
<h1 id="im-at-the-end-of-my-rope">I’m at the end of my rope</h1>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[雅思# #口语# 常用原因&解释 -- 忙]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/ofsZryf1i</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/ofsZryf1i">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-28T16:19:08.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm preoccupied at the moment.</p>
<p>My schedule is full.</p>
<p>I've got too much going on.</p>
<p>I've got a lot to do.</p>
<p>I've got a lot on my plate.</p>
<p>I'm busy as a bee.</p>
<p>I'm tied up right now.</p>
<p>I'm swamped.</p>
<p>I'm overwhelmed.</p>
<p>I'm buried in work.</p>
<p>I'm knee-deep in (something).</p>
<p>I'm up to my ears in (something).</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# #口语# 常用原因&解释 -- 开心]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/p594OefSA</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/p594OefSA">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-28T16:14:16.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>雅思口语中，我们经常会需要表达自己的情绪，开心，但是我们不能一直使用happy，那么积累一些不同的近义词就极为重要。除了掌握单词的样子，还要学会发音和正确用法。</p>
<p>小烤鸭们当然不需要记这么多！只需要从中选出4-5个自己看着喜欢的，也能够发音发正确的即可。</p>
<h1 id="a">A</h1>
<p><strong>amused</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
例子：<br>
<em>She was very amused by/at your comments.</em><br>
**Toddlers don't need expensive toys and games to keep them amused. **</p>
<h1 id="b">B</h1>
<p><strong>beaming</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
used to describe a smile that is very wide and happy, or someone who is smiling in this way<br>
例子：<br>
<em>a beaming smile</em></p>
<p><strong>blissful</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
extremely or completely happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>We spent a blissful year together before things started to go wrong.</em><br>
<em>a blissful childhood/holiday</em><br>
<em>Everyone loves the blissful feeling of going to sleep.</em><br>
<em>We spent a blissful evening at the beach.</em></p>
<p><strong>blithe</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
happy and without worry<br>
例子：<br>
<em>She shows a blithe disregard  for danger.</em></p>
<p><strong>buoyant</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
happy and confident<br>
例子：<br>
**After reading the letter he was in a buoyant mood. **</p>
<h1 id="c">C</h1>
<p><strong>carefree</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
having no problems or not being worried about anything<br>
例子：<br>
<em>I remember my carefree student days.</em></p>
<p><strong>cheerful</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
(1) happy and positive<br>
例子：<br>
<em>He's usually fairly cheerful.</em><br>
<em>You're in a cheerful mood this morning.</em><br>
(2) a place or thing that makes you feel positive and happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>Turn that dreadful wailing music off and put on something cheerful.</em></p>
<p><strong>cheery</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
bright and happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>She walked in with a cheery &quot;Good morning!&quot;</em><br>
<em>He gave us a cheery wave as we drove past.</em></p>
<p><strong>chipper</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>You seem mighty chipper this morning. what's up?</em><br>
*The dog seems very chipper. he won't stop playing. *<br>
<em>He's in a chipper mood because he has a date tonight.</em></p>
<p><strong>chirpy</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
happy and active<br>
例子：<br>
**She seemed quite chirpy this morning. **</p>
<p><strong>content</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
pleased with your situation and not hoping for change or improvement<br>
例子：<br>
**He seems fairly content with his life. **</p>
<p><strong>contented</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
happy and satisfied<br>
例子：<br>
<em>She smiled a contented smile.</em></p>
<h1 id="d">D</h1>
<p><strong>delighted</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very pleased<br>
例子：<br>
**Pat was delighted with her new house. **</p>
<h1 id="e">E</h1>
<p><strong>ebullient</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very energetic, positive , and happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>He wasn't his usual ebullient self.</em></p>
<p><strong>ecstatic</strong><br>
例子：<br>
<em>He was ecstatic when his wife gave birth to their first child.</em><br>
<em>Wes was ecstatic to see an FC Barcelona match.</em><br>
<em>We were ecstatic when we heard news of his promotion.</em></p>
<p><strong>elated</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
excited and happy combined<br>
例子：<br>
**The mother was elated when she watched her daughter's performance. **<br>
<em>He was elated after winning the context.</em></p>
<p><strong>enraptured</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
filled with great pleasure or extremely pleased by something<br>
例子：<br>
**The audience was enraptured by the young soloist's performance. **</p>
<p><strong>euphoric</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
a state of extreme happiness and joy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The dog felt euphoric as he ran into the water.</em><br>
**I watched an amazing sunrise and i felt euphoric. **</p>
<p><strong>exhilarated</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very excited and happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>At the end of the race i was exhilarated.</em></p>
<p><strong>exultant</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very happy, especially at someone else's defeat or failure<br>
例子：<br>
<em>an exultant cheer</em></p>
<h1 id="g">G</h1>
<p><strong>glad</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
pleased and delighted<br>
例子：<br>
<em>I am glad you came to the party.</em><br>
<em>I'll be glad to write you a letter of recommendation.</em></p>
<p><strong>gleeful</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
happy, excited, or pleased<br>
例子：<br>
<em>a gleeful smile/shout</em><br>
<em>I rubbed my hands in gleeful anticipation before settling down to sleep.</em></p>
<h1 id="i">I</h1>
<p><strong>in a good mood</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
feeling happy or pleasant<br>
例子：<br>
**People were in a good mood because progress was being made. **</p>
<p><strong>in good spirits</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
feeling happy or cheerful<br>
例子：<br>
<em>He seemed sad the last time i saw him, i'm glad he's in good spirits tonight.</em></p>
<p>***in seventh heaven ***<br>
英文解释<br>
extremely happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>Since they got married, they’re in seventh heaven .</em></p>
<p><strong>invigorated</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
to make someone feel fresher, healthier, and more energetic:<br>
例子：<br>
<em>We were invigorated by our walk.</em></p>
<h1 id="j">J</h1>
<p><strong>jaunty</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
showing that you are happy and confident<br>
例子：<br>
<em>a jaunty grin/step</em></p>
<p><strong>jocular</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
used to describe someone who is happy and likes to make jokes<br>
例子：<br>
<em>Michael was in a very jocular mood at the party.</em></p>
<p><strong>jolly</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
happy and cheerful<br>
例子：<br>
<em>Santa Claus is a jelly fellow.</em><br>
**My father is a jolly man. He's always laughing and joking. **</p>
<p><strong>jovial</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
(of a person) friendly and in a good mood, or (of a situation) enjoyable because of being friendly and pleasant:<br>
例子：<br>
<em>He seemed a very jovial guy.</em><br>
<em>a jovial time/evening/chat</em></p>
<p><strong>joyful</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
very happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The child's joyful laugh made us smile.</em><br>
**I had a joyful reaction when i saw the engagement ring. **</p>
<p><strong>joyous</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
full of joy; very happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>a joyous hymn/event/voice</em></p>
<p><strong>jubilant</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
feeling or expressing great happiness, especially because of a success<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The fans were jubilant at/about/over their team's victory.</em></p>
<h1 id="l">L</h1>
<p><strong>lighthearted</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
happy and not serious<br>
例子：<br>
**It was a fairly light-hearted discussion. **</p>
<p><strong>lively</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
full of life and energy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The small gathering of people turned into a lively party.</em></p>
<h1 id="m">M</h1>
<p><strong>merry</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
feeling or expressing great happiness, especially because of a success<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The fans were jubilant at/about/over their team's victory.</em></p>
<p><strong>mirthful</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
full of laughter, humour, or happiness:<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The ending of the film is melancholy rather than mirthful.</em></p>
<h1 id="o">O</h1>
<p><strong>on cloud nine</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
to be extremely happy and excited:<br>
例子：<br>
*When XX came home with a rescue kitten. XX was on cloud nine. *<br>
<em>He was on cloud nine after passing his drivers license test.</em></p>
<p><strong>on top of the world</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
extremely happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>We finally bought the house of our dreams, i'm on top of the world.</em></p>
<p><strong>over-the-moon</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
to be very pleased<br>
例子：<br>
<em>I can't believe i got the job! i'm over the moon.</em><br>
*She was over the moon about/with her new bike. *<br>
<em>She was over the moon when she found out she was pregnant.</em><br>
<em>He was over the moon when he finished graduate school.</em></p>
<p><strong>overjoyed</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
extremely happy<br>
例子：<br>
<em>I'm overjoyed that i've been accepted into university.</em><br>
We're overjoyed at your news.</p>
<h1 id="p">P</h1>
<p><strong>pleased</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
happy or satisfied<br>
例子：<br>
<em>I'm pleased to hear you're feeling better.</em><br>
<em>You could tell from her voice that she wasn't pleased.</em></p>
<h1 id="r">R</h1>
<p><strong>radiant</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
obviously very happy, or very beautiful<br>
例子：<br>
<em>He gave a radiant smile when he heard her news.</em><br>
<em>The bride looked radiant on her wedding day.</em></p>
<p><strong>rapturous</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
showing extreme pleasure and happiness or excitement:<br>
例子：<br>
<em>The play was greeted with rapturous applause.</em><br>
<em>The team received a rapturous welcome.</em></p>
<h1 id="s">S</h1>
<p><strong>satisfied</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
pleased because you have got what you wanted, or because something has happened in the way that you wanted<br>
例子：<br>
<em>A satisfied smile</em><br>
<em>Are you satisfied with the new arrangement?</em></p>
<p><strong>sunny</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
a sunny person is usually happy and relaxed and does not usually get worried or angry<br>
例子：<br>
**She has a very sunny disposition. **</p>
<h1 id="t">T</h1>
<p><strong>thrilled</strong><br>
英文解释<br>
extremely happy about something<br>
例子：<br>
<em>She was thrilled when she heard the good news.</em><br>
<em>I was thrilled that so many people turned up to the party.</em><br>
<em>He's thrilled to go skydiving for the first time.</em></p>
<p><strong>tickled pink</strong><br>
英文解释 imfml<br>
very pleased<br>
例子：<br>
**I was tickled pink to be invited. **</p>
<h1 id="u">U</h1>
<p><strong>upbeat</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
full of hope, happiness, and good feeling<br>
例子：<br>
<em>Live music and a parade set an upbeat mood for the official opening.</em><br>
<em>The song was really upbeat and put us in a good mood.</em><br>
<em>Even though the flight got cancelled, she remains upbeat about the situation.</em></p>
<h1 id="w">W</h1>
<p><strong>walking on air</strong><br>
英文解释：<br>
to be very happy and excited because something very good has happened to you<br>
例子：<br>
*Ever since she met Mark, she's been walking on air. *<br>
<em>They were walking on air after winning the match.</em><br>
<em>She was walking on air when she finished her exams.</em></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[# #雅思# #词汇#  2019年9月-12月]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/AEA4vKq30</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/AEA4vKq30">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-20T09:32:12.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="amusement-park">Amusement park</h1>
<p>在游乐园里玩不要用play<br>
a ride/rides; to ride</p>
<p><strong>可以玩的项目</strong><br>
a Ferris wheel<br>
a roller coaster<br>
bumper cars<br>
a drop tower<br>
a ‘haunted house’<br>
a merry-go-round<br>
a shooting gallery</p>
<p><strong>玩的动作</strong><br>
have all sorts of adventures<br>
go for a spin in some bumper cars<br>
go for a ride in the xxx<br>
enjoy firework display in the evening<br>
throw myself into various entertainment facilities<br>
watch singing and dancing performance<br>
take pictures with my favorite cartoon characters</p>
<p><strong>感受</strong><br>
scary rides<br>
excitement; exciting<br>
they are exhilarating<br>
thrilling<br>
pumped 兴奋<br>
heart-stopping<br>
to scream 尖叫<br>
nausea  n. 恶心，反胃的<br>
nauseous  adj.  恶心的，反胃的<br>
the spinning makes me nauseous. 转来转去的让我想吐。<br>
to vomit<br>
to feel giddy  感到头晕眼花的<br>
fear of heights  恐高<br>
jammed with noisy children<br>
queue up</p>
<p><strong>原因</strong><br>
have a blast for a whole day<br>
it's a getaway from the hectic work/study.<br>
pricy<br>
the best way to escape a monotonous routine and have a stress-free day<br>
foster bonding with friends and family</p>
<p><em><strong>To be continued</strong></em></p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#语法# #也#  also, as well, too, either]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/qaOcRWred</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/qaOcRWred">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-14T08:47:34.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>在英语中，also, as well, too, either 都有“也”的意思，但是在使用方法上却不尽相同。总的来说，前三个用于表达肯定意思中的“也”，最后一个表达的是否定意思中的“也”。下面，我们就来看看具体的不同之处。</p>
<h1 id="1also">1.	Also</h1>
<p>常用于写作中，少用于口语中<br>
位置：句首，句中&amp;句末</p>
<p>句首：强调后面的句子或是新加入的观点，后面应该加上逗号。</p>
<p><em>It’s very humid. Also, you can easily get sunburnt.<br>
那里（空气）很潮湿，同时，你也很容易晒伤。</em></p>
<p>句中：用作副词，在主语和主动词之间，或者在情态动词&amp;第一个助动词之后。作用是连接之后的从句。</p>
<p><em>She works very hard but she also goes to the gym every week.<br>
她工作很努力，但是她同时也每周都去一次健身房。</em></p>
<p><em>I’ve been working in the garden this week, and I’ve also been reading a lot.<br>
我这周一直在整修花园，我同时也在一直读书。</em></p>
<p>句尾：连接两个短句。在口语中我们常用as well &amp; too替代also。</p>
<p><em>She contacted him in the office but he didn’t answer the phone. His mobile phone was silent also. (or His mobile phone was silent too. or … was silent as well.)<br>
她在办公室里给他打电话，但是他没有接，他的手机是在静音的状态。（用too, as well, 也可以）</em></p>
<h1 id="2as-well">2.	As well</h1>
<p>常用于口语中，少用于写作中<br>
位置：常用于句尾,不要放在句首。</p>
<p><em>I just ignored it. I think everybody else did as well.<br>
<s>Not: As well I think everybody else did.</s></em></p>
<h1 id="3too">3.	Too</h1>
<p>位置：常用于句尾，也可在句中</p>
<p>句尾：<br>
<em>Gill’s having chicken. I’ll probably have chicken too.<br>
Gill 要吃鸡肉，我应该也吃鸡肉。</em></p>
<p><em>She looks really tired and she must be really hungry too.<br>
她看起来很累，她应该也很饿的吧。</em></p>
<p>句中：直接跟在主语之后，如果直接修饰主语的话。不跟在情态动词和助动词之后。</p>
<p><em>I too thought she looked unwell.<br>
我也认为她看起来气色不是很好。</em></p>
<p><em>We, too, have been very pleased to receive the prize on her behalf.<br>
我们也很开心可以代表她领奖。<br>
<s>Not: We have too been very pleased …</s><br>
不是这样的表述方式。</em></p>
<h1 id="4either">4.	Either</h1>
<p>用法一：否定含义的“也”</p>
<p><em>Bill’s not here. I don’t think Dave is either, is he?<br>
bill不在这里，我感觉Dave应该也不在的吧，对不对？<br>
<s>Not: I don’t think Dave is also/as well/too.</s><br>
不是这样的表述方式。</em></p>
<p><em>She doesn’t like eggs and she doesn’t like fish either.<br>
她不喜欢鸡蛋，她也不喜欢鱼。</em></p>
<p><em>It was a really nice hotel, and it wasn’t very expensive either.<br>
这个酒店很好，而且价格也不贵。</em></p>
<p>用法二：either .. or … 提供不同选项或者替代方案</p>
<p><em>We can eat either beef or pork.<br>
我们可以吃牛肉或者猪肉。</em></p>
<p>下面，我们可以看一些小练习额～</p>
<ol>
<li>I must buy a new phone ______.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>Wesley is a strong boy. ______, he is very generous.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>I’m going to Japan next week and my sister’s going _____.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
<li>He can’t surf; he can’t swim ______.<br>
A. Also B. Too C. As well D. Either</li>
</ol>
<p>答案是 :</p>
<ol>
<li>B,C</li>
<li>A</li>
<li>B,C</li>
<li>D</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[#雅思# 完美9分答案]]></title>
        <id>https://JuneMY.github.io/post/iy_Ge4zRw</id>
        <link href="https://JuneMY.github.io/post/iy_Ge4zRw">
        </link>
        <updated>2019-12-02T11:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>很多小烤鸭们不是很清楚自己的英语会是属于哪个水平的，那么下边的就是一个完美9分答案的展示。建议可以自己先试着回答一下问题，然后拿着自己的跟这个答案对比一下，学习这里面的好词好句，争取转化成是自己的！</p>
<p align="center"><iframe style="float:middle" height="50" width="260"src="https://www.ximalaya.com/thirdparty/player/sound/player.html?id=233698642&type=red" frameborder=0 allowfullscreen></iframe></p >
<h1 id="只有问题">只有问题</h1>
<h2 id="part-1">Part 1</h2>
<p>Can you tell me your full name, please?<br>
can you tell me where you’re from?<br>
Can I see your identification, please?</p>
<p>Can you tell me about the kind of music you like?<br>
Where do you like to listen to music?<br>
Why do you think music is so important in many people’s lives?</p>
<p>What’s the best way to get around your city?<br>
Have you ever learned to drive?<br>
Do you think everybody should learn to drive?</p>
<h2 id="part-2">Part 2</h2>
<p>Describe something difficult you learned to do.<br>
You should say:<br>
– what you learned to do<br>
– how you learned to do it<br>
– why it was difficult<br>
and explain whether you’re glad that you learned to do this or not.</p>
<h2 id="part-3">Part 3</h2>
<p>What motivates people to learn new things?<br>
Do you think the way that people learn new things has changed compared to the past?<br>
How do you think technology will change the way people learn new things in the future?<br>
How can parents or students choose the best school or university?<br>
How do people in your country feel about private education?<br>
Do you think that university education should be free?</p>
<h1 id="问题答案">问题&amp;答案</h1>
<h2 id="part-1-2">Part 1</h2>
<p>Examiner: Hello, my name is ---. This is the IELTS speaking test. Can you tell me your full name, please?<br>
Student: My name’s ---.</p>
<p>Examiner: And can you tell me where you’re from?<br>
Student: I’m from a small town near Northampton, in the UK.</p>
<p>Examiner: Can I see your identification, please?<br>
Student: Yes, of course. Here you are.</p>
<p>Examiner: Okay, thank you very much. Now, in this first part I’d like to know something about you. First of all, can you tell me about the kind of music you like?<br>
Student: Sure, well, I’m a big fan of what you might call alternative electronica. It’s hard to classify, because when you say ‘electronica’, people think of dance music, but I wouldn’t call it that. Basically, I listen to a lot of stuff with hip-hop, funk or disco influences, but most of my friends think my taste in music is a bit weird.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. And, where do you like to listen to music?<br>
Student: I listen to music pretty much any time that I’m at home. So, if I’m doing housework, or cooking, or anything like that, I’ll put some music on. Sometimes I also listen to music on the bus. Especially if I’m going to play sport or to the gym, I’ll listen to some high-energy tunes on the way to get myself pumped up.</p>
<p>Examiner: Yeah, okay. Why do you think music is so important in many people’s lives?<br>
Student: Hmm… That’s a big question… [pause] Well, first of all music has always been part of human culture, so in that sense obviously it’s an important part of our lives. I guess that’s because music can have such a powerful effect on our emotions. Music can lift you up, or inspire you, or make you feel sad. I’d certainly find it hard to live without it!</p>
<p>Examiner: Uh-huh. I’d like to move on and talk about transport. What’s the best way to get around your city?<br>
Student: I live in quite a small town, so it’s very easy to get around. You can walk or cycle to a lot of places, although some roads are a bit dangerous for bikes. There are buses which are fairly reliable, but they’re not the fastest way to get around. Finally, you can take a taxi or an Uber if you want to get somewhere fast and you don’t mind paying a bit extra.</p>
<p>Examiner: Alright. And, have you ever learned to drive?<br>
Student: Yes, I learned in the UK as soon as I was old enough, although I have to say I haven’t driven for several years! I’m not sure if you’d want to get in a car with me, but I guess I’d pick it up again quite quickly. There’s just not much point in having a car where I am now, because I can walk or ride my bike around town, and take public transport if I want to go somewhere else, for the weekend or whatever.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. Do you think everybody should learn to drive?<br>
Student: Er… That’s a strange idea. I think it’s up to each person to decide. It can be very useful in some places. For example, where I grew up in the UK… It’s a rural area, and if you don’t have a car you’re pretty isolated. If you live somewhere like that, you should probably learn to drive. But, it’s still a choice, right?</p>
<h2 id="part-2-2">Part 2</h2>
<p>Examiner: Now, I’m going to give you a topic and I’d like you to talk about it for one to two minutes. You have one minute to think about what you are going to say. You can make some notes to help you if you wish.</p>
<p>Describe something difficult you learned to do.<br>
You should say:<br>
– what you learned to do<br>
– how you learned to do it<br>
– why it was difficult<br>
and explain whether you’re glad that you learned to do this or not.</p>
<p>Examiner: Are you ready?<br>
Student: Yes.<br>
Examiner: Okay, please tell me about something difficult you learned to do.</p>
<p>Student: So, I’m going to tell you about learning to drive a car with manual transmission. I’m from the States, and almost no one drives a manual there; most cars are automatic. When I came to Europe, I found it was totally the opposite here; driving a manual is the norm, and automatics are rare. I guess here they’re associated with very expensive, luxury cars. Anyway, I had to learn to drive stick, and it was so difficult! It was doubly hard because I already knew how to drive, so it felt extra frustrating to be behind the wheel but unable to do the things I would normally do. Maybe it wasn’t a good idea but I didn’t get any help; I could have gone to a driving school but I didn’t. I just practiced and tried to learn by myself, by driving around car parks and open spaces and things like that. That was okay, but when I went out and drove properly, on the streets with traffic, it was super stressful. I just couldn’t get the clutch right, and then I’d stall and I’d be stressing out while everyone was honking at me. I can’t say that I’m glad that I learned it. I mean, I just learned to do it because I had to, and I didn’t enjoy the experience! If it were up to me, I’d rather just have an automatic car.</p>
<p>Examiner: Thank you. So, what do you use your car for?<br>
Student: Mostly for getting to work. I live quite far from the nearest metro station and the bus lines aren’t good, so it’s much easier to drive. Sometimes we go out of town for the weekends, too.</p>
<h2 id="part-3-2">Part 3</h2>
<p>Examiner: Right, I’d like to ask some questions related to this topic. First, let’s talk about learning new things. What motivates people to learn new things?<br>
Student: Wow… that’s a big question! Well, there are lots of reasons. The main one I guess is just necessity. For example, if you want to work in a particular field, you’ll need some specific training, skills, qualifications… Then, when you start a new job, you generally have to adapt and learn a lot of new things, even if you came in with a lot of theoretical knowledge. What else? I think also interest is important… I mean, people learn to do new things because they’re interested in them or they find something enjoyable. For example, no one needs to learn to play a musical instrument, but a lot of people do so because it brings them pleasure.</p>
<p>Examiner: Do you think the way that people learn new things has changed compared to the past?<br>
Student: Absolutely. Of course, the Internet and the development of smartphones and other new technologies have had a huge influence. We all have easy access to so much information now, which wasn’t the case in the past at all. Before, people would need to dedicate a lot of time and effort to finding an expert, or doing research in order to learn about something new. Now, you can find tutorials online, ask people for help in discussion forums, and things like that. So, it’s a big difference, but I think it’s mostly for the better.</p>
<p>Examiner: How do you think technology will change the way people learn new things in the future?<br>
Student: Hmm… I’m not sure. I think we’ll see the same trends developing… What I mean is: the big changes have already happened, but I don’t think they’ve run their course yet. So, a lot of people still have the idea that you learn something by going to a class, reading books, etc., and they haven’t realised that you just have more options nowadays. To tie all this together, I think that in the future, education and learning will be more globalised and democratic, in that everybody will have similar opportunities to learn. I suppose that might mean that formal education diminishes in significance, but I’m not sure that will actually happen.</p>
<p>Examiner: Okay, let’s move on to talk about school and education. How can parents or students choose the best school or university?<br>
Student: In my experience, the only way to know what a school or university is really like is to talk to people who already study there and see what they say. Of course, you can go and look around, but I don’t think you can learn very much just by walking around a school. If you talk to some of the staff and students, you can get a feel of what kind of establishment it is, and whether it’s a good fit for you, or your child, whoever you’re talking about.</p>
<p>Examiner: Mm-hmm. How do people in your country feel about private education?<br>
Student: Huh… I really don’t know. I went to a public school, and so did everyone I know. It’s not really a topic which comes up that much, you know? Personally, I don’t have strong opinions; if someone wants to pay to send their child to a private school, then why not? Given that there aren’t that many private schools, it’s just not something that people are so aware of.</p>
<p>Examiner: I see. Do you think that university education should be free?<br>
Student: Definitely, yes. In the USA, university is insanely expensive; parents have to start saving up from the moment their child is born. I think this leads to elitist outcomes… I mean that the richest kids go to the best universities, and if you don’t have a lot of money behind you, your options are more limited. That said, I realize that graduates tend to earn more, so it might be fairer to have some kind of graduate tax, so that the people who erm… benefit from higher education also help to fund it. That seems to me to be the fairest solution.<br>
Examiner: Thank you. That’s the end of the speaking test.</p>
<p>好的，看完了吗？自己感觉怎么样呢？要注意积累好的用法额！～<br>
学习之路漫漫，加油！～</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>